<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <item><title>Moscow, Caracas reiterate brotherly ties, strategic cooperation — top Venezuelan diplomat</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063379</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063379</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>"During the phone call with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, we again reiterated our brotherly relations, mutual respect, and strategic partnership between us," Yvan Gil Pinto said</description></item><item><title>Netanyahu to discuss Iran’s nuclear activities, next phase of Gaza plan with Trump</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337396/netanyahu-discuss-irans-nuclear-activities-next-phase-gaza-plan-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337396/netanyahu-discuss-irans-nuclear-activities-next-phase-gaza-plan-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:33:22 +0000</pubDate><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on ‍Monday he will discuss Iran’s nuclear activities during his visit next week with US President Donald Trump.
Speaking at a joint press conference with Greek Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis and Cypriot President Nikos Christodoulides in Jerusalem, Netanyahu said Israel was aware Iran had been conducting “exercises” recently, without elaborating.
Earlier on Monday, Iranian state media reported Iran had held missile drills in various cities...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/eb3b8546-b8c7-4182-b91e-2a53d60147fe_638ed991.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Poland to build training range for joint maneuvers with Lithuania in Suwalki Gap</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063369</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063369</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:34:40 +0000</pubDate><description>"There are no other examples of such facilities in Europe," Lithuanian Vice-minister of National Defense Bronius Bieliauskas said</description></item><item><title>Venezuela reiterates its commitment to peace, but will defend its sovereignty — Maduro</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063371</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063371</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:40:11 +0000</pubDate><description>The president recalled that the US military had staged 28 attacks on civilian ships in the Caribbean and the eastern Pacific, "executing 104 people extrajudicially" and stressed that Venezuela had done nothing that could justify the United States’ military pressure</description></item><item><title>Christmas in Europe to be peaceful, but military threat remains — Hungarian leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063377</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063377</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:43:01 +0000</pubDate><description>Preparations for a war with Russia "are still under way in Europe behind closed doors," Viktor Orban said</description></item><item><title>London recklessly provokes US into confrontation with Russia — UK journalist</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063219</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063219</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Frank Wright said "it's not realistic for the Europeans or the British to win a war against Russia"</description></item><item><title>Top Turkish diplomat says phase two of Gaza deal may begin in early 2026</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063365</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063365</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:36:46 +0000</pubDate><description>The transfer of power to the Palestinians is at the top of the agenda now, noted Hakan Fidan</description></item><item><title>UK man, 5 others charged with more than 60 sex offences against woman</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337394/uk-man-5-others-charged-more-60-sex-offences-against-woman?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337394/uk-man-5-others-charged-more-60-sex-offences-against-woman?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:02:22 +0000</pubDate><description>A British man was charged on Monday with drugging and raping his ex-wife, and five other men were charged with sexual offences against her over a 13-year period, UK police said.
Philip Young, 49, will appear on Tuesday at a court in Swindon, west of London, charged with dozens of offences against his 48-year-old former spouse Joanne Young, who has waived her legal right to anonymity.
The alleged offences include multiple counts of rape and administering a substance with intent to stupefy or...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/5d65f0d1-31d3-41a3-858a-1d9ee95c2473_839829be.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Two civilians die after Kurds shell Aleppo — TV</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063349</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063349</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:50:17 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the repot, the shelling attack targeted Aleppo’s northern Al-Jamiliya neighborhood</description></item><item><title>CIS leaders note importance of strengthening cultural dialogue — Uzbekistan's leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063335</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063335</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:06:47 +0000</pubDate><description>The heads of the CIS states earlier visited the exposition of artistic silver, as well as the Alexander, Picket and Coat of Arms Halls</description></item><item><title>Trump administration to recall 48 heads of diplomatic missions — NYP</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063337</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063337</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:08:11 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, the Trump administration has not yet appointed the heads of diplomatic missions in its key partner countries</description></item><item><title>Top Democrat urges Senate to sue over Justice Department’s staggered Epstein files release</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337393/top-democrat-urges-senate-sue-over-justice-departments-staggered-epstein-files-release?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337393/top-democrat-urges-senate-sue-over-justice-departments-staggered-epstein-files-release?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:08:42 +0000</pubDate><description>Chuck Schumer, the Senate’s top Democrat, urged his colleagues on Monday to take legal action over the Justice Department’s incremental and heavily redacted release of records pertaining to the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.
Schumer introduced a resolution that, if passed, would direct the Senate to file or join lawsuits aimed at forcing the Justice Department to comply with the Epstein Files Transparency Act, the law enacted last month that required disclosure of records by last...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/924df5a6-c36e-46bb-9dfa-b790c1a927f4_67f340b2.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Europe lacks money to sponsor Kiev, needs to look for compromise — French MP</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063339</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063339</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:09:01 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Thierry Mariani, today, little depends on Europe as far as the Ukrainian settlement is concerned</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian parliament speaker moves to begin legislative process on holding elections</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063345</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063345</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Ruslan Stefanchuk, the biggest thing will be to create conditions for the military to vote at the front and their right to be elected</description></item><item><title>Ex-Israeli PM accuses Netanyahu of ‘treason’ over alleged Qatar funding to aides</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337391/ex-israeli-pm-accuses-netanyahu-treason-over-alleged-qatar-funding-aides?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337391/ex-israeli-pm-accuses-netanyahu-treason-over-alleged-qatar-funding-aides?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:01:44 +0000</pubDate><description>Former Israeli premier Naftali Bennett, widely regarded as a leading contender in next year’s legislative elections, called on Monday for the resignation of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, accusing his office of “treason” over alleged Qatari funding to his aides.
Netanyahu has also announced he intends to seek another term in office ahead of the legislative elections scheduled for October 2026.
At the centre of the controversy is the “Qatargate” affair, in which close associates of Netanyahu...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/7ff4f6b0-6a50-4eea-b231-ca53944992ac_90445bdd.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Tanker seized by US near Venezuela towed to Texas port — TV</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063323</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063323</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:15:21 +0000</pubDate><description>The report says the vessel has been anchored approximately 50 miles from the port city of Galveston</description></item><item><title>Democrats to move to impeach Trump if they win Congress in 2026</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063327</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063327</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate><description>Speaker of the House of Representatives, member of the Republican Party Mike Johnson pointed out that the Democratic Party intends to "dismantle" the foundations of the country</description></item><item><title>UK street artist Banksy unveils latest mural in central London</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337392/uk-street-artist-banksy-unveils-latest-mural-central-london?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337392/uk-street-artist-banksy-unveils-latest-mural-central-london?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:29:02 +0000</pubDate><description>British street artist Banksy unveiled his latest work in central London on Monday amid speculation over an identical second work which has appeared elsewhere in the city.
The black and white mural painted on the side of an old building in Bayswater shows two people, probably children, in winter hats and Wellington boots lying down, looking up and pointing to the sky.
Banksy, whose real identity has not been revealed, posted an image of the work on his official Instagram account on Monday.
A...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/da982691-9426-461e-91c1-313a302ad7e8_87570607.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Pashinyan sees nuances in Trump route implementation tied to Russia relations</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063301</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063301</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:43 +0000</pubDate><description>The Armenian Prime Minister said that Yerevan is engaged in constructive bilateral negotiations with the United States</description></item><item><title>Pashinyan thanks Putin for facilitating peace process with Azerbaijan</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063303</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063303</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate><description>The Armenian Prime Minister expressed confidence that peace between Armenia and Azerbaijan has already been achieved, as trains from Russia now travel to Armenia through Azerbaijani territory</description></item><item><title>‘Driving Home For Christmas’ singer Chris Rea dies at 74</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337389/driving-home-christmas-singer-chris-rea-dies-74?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337389/driving-home-christmas-singer-chris-rea-dies-74?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:31:49 +0000</pubDate><description>British singer Chris Rea, whose songs include the festive hit “Driving Home For Christmas”, has died at the age of 74, a spokesperson for his family said on Monday.
The Middlesbrough-born musician was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer and had his pancreas removed in 2001, and in 2016 he suffered a stroke.
Rea found fame in the late 1970s and 1980s with hits such as “Fool (If You Think It’s Over)”, “Let’s Dance” and “The Road to Hell”.
A statement from his family to the Press Association said:...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/7d6b639f-ef50-4754-8976-00057f4318f4_fa17e534.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Europe stagnates culturally and economically — Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063313</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063313</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President added that Europe's immigration policies have caused a significant backlash from the native population</description></item><item><title>Paramount vs Netflix: Ellison guarantees US$40 billion for son’s Warner Bros bid</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337388/paramount-vs-netflix-ellison-guarantees-us40-billion-sons-warner-bros-bid?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337388/paramount-vs-netflix-ellison-guarantees-us40-billion-sons-warner-bros-bid?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>Oracle tech tycoon Larry Ellison is offering a US$40.4 billion personal guarantee to back Paramount’s hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery, deepening a bidding war with Netflix, a statement said on Monday.
The amended proposal, worth a total US$108 billion from the company run by Ellison’s son David, addresses concerns raised by Warner Bros’ board, which saw the Paramount bid as too risky and asked shareholders to accept a competing buyout offer from Netflix.
Netflix shocked the industry on...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/c1c045bf-b3ec-4647-8f72-a9a5b4be2fed_44f09af1.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Two US mercenaries eliminated in Ukraine — Newsweek</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063289</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063289</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:45:43 +0000</pubDate><description>According to reports from the accounts of the families of the deceased, Jones and Zacherl were serving with international forces under the command of Ukraine's GUR military intelligence agency</description></item><item><title>Slovakia refuses to vote nay on EU's Ukraine financing plan — PM</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063273</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063273</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:12:40 +0000</pubDate><description>Robert Fico and other members of the Slovak government have repeatedly stated that the country insists on an immediate ceasefire and peace negotiations while refusing to finance the continuation of the conflict</description></item><item><title>Nigeria says ‘spat’ with Trump over killing of Christians ‘largely resolved’</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337384/nigeria-says-spat-trump-over-killing-christians-largely-resolved?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337384/nigeria-says-spat-trump-over-killing-christians-largely-resolved?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:45:55 +0000</pubDate><description>The Nigerian government on Monday said its recent diplomatic dust-up with the United States, in which President Donald Trump threatened military intervention over the alleged killing of Christians, “has been largely resolved”.
Trump unexpectedly tore into the west African nation in October and November, saying that Christians there faced an “existential threat” that amounted to “genocide” amid Nigeria’s myriad armed conflicts.
The diplomatic offensive was welcomed by some but interpreted by...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/155b6caa-6a7a-4f15-b145-3683cfa3907e_500ba570.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukraine deal close, but most difficult issues remain unresolved — Finnish leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063213</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063213</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:07:21 +0000</pubDate><description>According to media reports, Alexander Stubb has maintained close contact with US President Donald Trump</description></item><item><title>Certain countries, politicians oppose Trump's Ukraine peace plan — Georgian official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063229</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063229</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:10:45 +0000</pubDate><description>Kakha Kaladze declined to specify which countries and politicians are obstructing Trump's efforts to end the Ukraine war</description></item><item><title>Kiev acknowledges that it will probably lose Donetsk — JD Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063227</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063227</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:11:34 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President suggested that territorial concessions "could be 12 months from now, it could be longer than that," stating that "territorial concession is a significant hold-up in the negotiations"</description></item><item><title>Trump administration triples ‘self-deport’ stipend to US$3,000</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337382/trump-administration-triples-self-deport-stipend-us3000?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337382/trump-administration-triples-self-deport-stipend-us3000?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:14:46 +0000</pubDate><description>The Trump administration has tripled its stipend offer to migrants who choose to voluntarily “self-deport” ‌from the United States to US$3,000, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) ‍said on Monday.
The stipend would be given to people in the US illegally who sign up to leave the country by the end of the ⁠year, DHS said. The offer would include a free flight back to their home countries, it said.
“Illegal aliens should take advantage of this gift and self-deport because if they don’t, we...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/aee8995f-d299-48c6-995d-fa11d4775ee6_8a0760e7.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Uganda plans to gradually abolish visas for Russians — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063185</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063185</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate><description>At present, visas are processed online and issued within two days</description></item><item><title>No free elections in Ukraine until Russians returned their rights — opposition politician</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063173</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063173</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:49:39 +0000</pubDate><description>"Zelensky has every lever at his disposal to curb and distort the will of the people and impose his conditions on the country in his personal concentration camp," Viktor Medvedchuk said</description></item><item><title>Up to ten Oreshnik systems to be deployed in Belarus — president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063191</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063191</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:56:22 +0000</pubDate><description>Alexander Lukashenko said an Oreshnik system has entered combat duty in the republic and denied media reports that it was deployed in Slutsk</description></item><item><title>Vance rings alarm bell over growing 'Islamist' presence in European politics</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063059</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063059</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:04:34 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President also warned of potential long-term risks to Europe-Washington relations across various fields</description></item><item><title>Hungarian PM objects to sending tax dollars to Ukraine, advocates spending money at home</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063071</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063071</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:14:20 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban has repeatedly confirmed that his government calls for resolving the Ukraine conflict peacefully and has no plans to spend Hungarian taxpayer money on further military activities in the country</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian soldiers deserting due to being underpaid — outlet</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063137</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063137</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:14:51 +0000</pubDate><description>A serviceman suggested that AWOL could become an even more widespread phenomenon in the Ukrainian army in the coming months</description></item><item><title>Did CBS postpone a ‘60 Minutes’ report on El Salvador prison for ‘political’ reasons?</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337379/did-cbs-postpone-60-minutes-report-el-salvador-prison-political-reasons?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337379/did-cbs-postpone-60-minutes-report-el-salvador-prison-political-reasons?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:38:22 +0000</pubDate><description>CBS News pulled a 60 Minutes report on El Salvador’s CECOT prison just hours before its ‍scheduled Sunday broadcast, saying it would air at a future time.
“The broadcast line-up for tonight’s edition of 60 Minutes has been updated,” the programme posted on social media. “Our report ‘Inside CECOT’ will air in a future broadcast,” the programme posted on social media three hours before it was slated to air.
A CBS News spokesperson said in ⁠an email that the segment “needed additional reporting”....</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/593db9f2-4637-4df3-be5c-a00c5602cbf9_84afa89d.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Pentagon deems Lakenheath base in England unfit for nuclear weapons — media</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063007</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063007</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate><description>The authors of the document noted that one reason Lakenheath cannot host nuclear weapons is that "some of those involved in the US nuclear operation would not have quick access to a toilet during an Armageddon-style scenario"</description></item><item><title>US, Israel may face significant disagreements despite their alliance — JD Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063009</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063009</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:01:40 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President said that it is important for Washington to maintain room for maneuver in its relations with the Jewish state and to have the ability to distance itself from its foreign policy at certain stages</description></item><item><title>Japan’s nuclear ambitions undermine stability in Asia Pacific — Chinese MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063013</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063013</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:06:03 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Lin Jian, Beijing believes that it is unacceptable for Japan to undermine the international nuclear non-proliferation regime, citing fictitious threats</description></item><item><title>Vance indicates breakthrough in Ukraine talks between Russia, United States</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063019</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063019</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:10:04 +0000</pubDate><description>The US vice president said that America would continue to make diplomatic efforts towards a Ukraine resolution</description></item><item><title>Macron played key role in derailing EU plan on Russian assets at summit — Politico</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063023</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063023</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:19:35 +0000</pubDate><description>At the summit, the French leader held discussions with Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, the report stated</description></item><item><title>Ukraine talks progress, territorial issues: statements by US vice president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063025</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063025</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:22:28 +0000</pubDate><description>JD Vance noted progress on the Ukraine front during the negotiations with Russian Presidential Special Envoy Kirill Dmitriev in Miami</description></item><item><title>Iran’s missile program will never be up for discussion or bargaining — Foreign Ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063031</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063031</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:30:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Iranian Foreign Ministry Spokesman Esmail Baghaei argued that Western demands for restrictions on Iran’s missile program are nothing but double standards</description></item><item><title>Europe pressures Kiev to stem departure of youth to other countries — newspaper</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063033</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063033</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate><description>El Pais also characterizes Ukraine’s demographic situation as catastrophic</description></item><item><title>Thailand, Cambodia to discuss ceasefire deal on Wednesday</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063035</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063035</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:33:12 +0000</pubDate><description>Thai Foreign Minister Sihasak Phuangketkeow said these talks will be conducted within the framework of the existing Joint Border Committee</description></item><item><title>Denmark angered over Trump naming envoy to Greenland, summons US ambassador</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337363/denmark-angered-over-trump-naming-envoy-greenland-summons-us-ambassador?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337363/denmark-angered-over-trump-naming-envoy-greenland-summons-us-ambassador?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:54:25 +0000</pubDate><description>The Danish foreign minister said on Monday he will summon the US ambassador, insisting that everyone – including the United States – must respect “the territorial integrity of the Kingdom of Denmark” after US President Donald Trump announced the appointment of Louisiana’s governor as the US ‌special envoy to Greenland.
During his presidential transition and early second term, Trump repeatedly pushed for US control over Greenland, a semi-autonomous Danish territory, and has not ruled out using...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/368ce758-de9e-49ca-bf1d-08fa974d3d42_c2bb63f9.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US State Department denies plans to allocate $60 billion for Gaza's reconstruction</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062957</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062957</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:06:26 +0000</pubDate><description>The State Department, nonetheless, does not deny the existence of a Gaza reconstruction plan</description></item><item><title>No peace deal reached between Cambodia, Thailand at meeting in Malaysia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062979</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062979</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:12:24 +0000</pubDate><description>The negotiations reached a deadlock after the Thai side demanded that Cambodia fulfill three conditions to end hostilities</description></item><item><title>Iran continues to demand IAEA condemn Israeli strikes on nuclear facilities — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062975</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062975</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:12:53 +0000</pubDate><description>Esmail Baghaei pointed out that the agency’s failure to condemn the Israeli attacks not only indicates indifference to these illegal acts but also potentially signals to Israel that such aggression may be repeated</description></item><item><title>Iran promises not to break off relations with Russia at Europe’s request</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062983</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062983</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:14:42 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Esmaeil Baghaei, European countries should pay attention to their behavior and analyze why the conflict in Ukraine arose in the first place</description></item><item><title>Death toll in Indonesia floods exceeds 1,100 — agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062949</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062949</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:47:53 +0000</pubDate><description>About 7,000 people were injured</description></item><item><title>Uganda wants to cooperate with Russia in oil, gas sector — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062953</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062953</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:53:06 +0000</pubDate><description>The African country also intends to develop trade with Russia in many areas</description></item><item><title>US Department of Justice plans no redactions in Epstein files to project famous people</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062925</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062925</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:05:19 +0000</pubDate><description>The agency pointed out that some of the material was temporarily removed based on requests from victims and their lawyers</description></item><item><title>New French missile could form basis of European 'nuclear umbrella,' expert says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062921</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062921</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:08:56 +0000</pubDate><description>Alexander Stepanov pointed out that the ASMPA-R has successfully completed tests with the Rafale M carrier-based aircraft, confirming its operational compatibility</description></item><item><title>EU loan to Kiev funds continuation of conflict — political director for Hungarian PM</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062891</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062891</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:14:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban argued that the move would ultimately lead to cuts in other areas of European countries’ budgets, emphasizing that Hungary will not participate in the loan</description></item><item><title>European leaders tend to delay decision making, Romanian president says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062865</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062865</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:16:43 +0000</pubDate><description>Nicusor Dan stressed that EU politics was a democratic process, but "the debates are a little bit too long"</description></item><item><title>Another 25 children added to Ukraine’s database of unwanted persons</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062881</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062881</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:34:35 +0000</pubDate><description>All of them were born between 2015 and 2021</description></item><item><title>White House launches livestream highlighting Trump administration’s 2025 achievements</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062887</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062887</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:46:58 +0000</pubDate><description>The US leader appears as an animated character, seated in an armchair next to a Christmas tree, surrounded by gifts, and reading a book</description></item><item><title>Drones entering Romania’s airspace pose no threat, president says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062883</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062883</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:47:20 +0000</pubDate><description>Nicusor Dan believes the drones that have been recorded in the country’s airspace have not intentionally been sent on its territory</description></item><item><title>Russian general killed in Moscow car bombing, investigators say</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337301/russian-general-killed-moscow-car-bombing-investigators-say?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337301/russian-general-killed-moscow-car-bombing-investigators-say?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:20:25 +0000</pubDate><description>A Russian general was killed on Monday morning after an explosive device detonated underneath his car in southern Moscow, investigators said.
Lieutenant General Fanil Sarvarov, head of the Operational Training Directorate of the Russian Armed Forces General Staff, died from his injuries, Svetlana Petrenko, official spokesperson for Russia’s Investigative Committee, said.
“Investigators are pursuing numerous lines of enquiry regarding the murder. One of these is that the crime was orchestrated by...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/fec8580a-7d9d-4d5c-9818-e19759e4e7d6_14a26ac0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukrainian authorities evacuate almost 147,000 civilians from frontline areas</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062839</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062839</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 06:08:01 +0000</pubDate><description>More than 16,500 of those evacuated are children</description></item><item><title>Critical infrastructure facility damaged in Ukrainian city of Odessa</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062835</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062835</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:24:52 +0000</pubDate><description>One of the city districts was partially left without electricity</description></item><item><title>Trump names Louisiana governor as US special envoy to Greenland</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062837</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062837</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:38:44 +0000</pubDate><description>The American leader has repeatedly said that Greenland should become a part of the United States</description></item><item><title>Conflict with Thailand leaves 525,000 Cambodians dispaced — ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062833</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062833</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>The number includes 274,800 women and 167,100 children</description></item><item><title>Scientist Hu Haitao leaves US for China, Mexico tariff shock: 5 weekend reads you missed</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:30:08 +0000</pubDate><description>We have put together stories from our coverage last weekend to help you stay informed about news across Asia and beyond. If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider subscribing.
1. Mexico’s 50% tariff shock shuts Asia’s North American trade bypass

2. China warns India: ‘don’t even think about stealing our 6th Dalai Lama’

3. Hong Kong district officer apologises over outfit choice at firefighter’s funeral

4. Thailand’s tourism crown slips as troubles in paradise mount

5....</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/c76f83e4-5116-402f-9126-a2d0b9c538c7_b474ee7b.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Republika Srpska’s new president maintains course of friendship with Russia — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062803</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062803</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:45:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Yury Pilipson recalled that "the early presidential elections in the Republika Srpska held on November 23 were the result of a campaign launched under pressure from Western countries to illegally remove Milorad Dodik, the leader of the Serbs in Bosnia and Herzegovina, from power"</description></item><item><title>No new Russia-US meeting on irritants planned yet — embassy in Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062805</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062805</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:19:57 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, US diplomats noted that Washington considers "the channel of bilateral operations as a constructive and permanent platform for negotiations to stabilize the work of the missions"</description></item><item><title>Brussels promised that sanctions would crush Russia, but they destroyed Europe — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062807</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062807</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:22:38 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that this is the price of poor decision-making and that negotiations are needed</description></item><item><title>European Commission becomes ‘Titanic’ dragging EU down with it — magazine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062817</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062817</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:34:06 +0000</pubDate><description>According to journalist Rafael Pinto Borges, Brussels has experienced institutional decline, which the European Commission prefers to ignore</description></item><item><title>Trump administration recalls heads of nearly 30 foreign diplomatic missions — news agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062819</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062819</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:03:54 +0000</pubDate><description>According to its information, the heads of US missions abroad have been notified that their terms in their current positions will expire in January</description></item><item><title>No Ukraine ceasefire breakthrough despite ‘productive and constructive’ talks</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:30:27 +0000</pubDate><description>US and Ukrainian envoys issued a joint statement on Sunday that hailed “productive and constructive” talks in Miami but did not announce any apparent breakthrough in efforts to end the war with Russia.
Top representatives from both Ukraine and Russia, as well as Kyiv’s European allies, have been in southern Florida over the past several days for a series of separate talks hosted by US President Donald Trump’s special envoy, Steve Witkoff.
The meetings were the latest in a weeks-long diplomatic...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/5cdf1648-0b89-46bb-b500-fb0b2c4cd139_b36102a0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US tanker with Venezuelan oil left for US — official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062821</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062821</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:51:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Vice President and Hydrocarbons Minister Delcy Rodriguez also posted a video of the tanker leaving port</description></item><item><title>Witkoff calls Russia-US consultations on Ukraine ‘productive, constructive’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062797</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062797</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:34:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Moscow highly values Washington's efforts to settle the conflict and strengthen global security, he added</description></item><item><title>US Air Force fighter jet intercepts aircraft for approaching Trump's residence</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062785</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062785</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate><description>F‑16 intercepted an aircraft that entered restricted airspace over Palm Beach, NORAD reported</description></item><item><title>Continuation of Ukraine conflict beneficial to politicians, arms dealers, bankers — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062787</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062787</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:14:57 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that Europeans deserve better, because Europe needs peace</description></item><item><title>US, Ukraine discuss sequence of next steps during consultations — Witkoff</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062769</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062769</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:44:21 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Special Representative of the US president, the parties, in particular, held "a separate constructive meeting"</description></item><item><title>Israeli foreign minister urges Jews to move to Israel a week after Sydney attack</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:11:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar called on Sunday for Jews in Western countries to move to Israel to escape rising antisemitism, one week after 15 were shot dead at a Jewish event in Sydney.
“Jews have the right to live in safety everywhere. But we see and fully understand what is happening, and we have a certain historical experience.
“Today, Jews are being hunted across the world,” Saar said at a public candle lighting marking the last day of the Jewish festival of Hanukkah.
“Today I call...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/e5780976-ffcf-4b84-b7f9-b4d3b9443b98_8ea3fbf3.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukrainian journalists say took pictures of Mindich in Israel</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062775</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062775</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:14:30 +0000</pubDate><description>The details are promised to be released later</description></item><item><title>Thousands cheer as the sun rises on winter solstice at Britain’s Stonehenge</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate><description>Thousands of people cheered and danced around Stonehenge as the sun rose over the prehistoric stone circle on Sunday, the winter solstice.
The crowds, many dressed as druids and pagans, had gathered before dawn, waiting patiently in the dark, cold field in Wiltshire, southwest England. Some sang and beat drums while others took time to reflect among the huge stone pillars.
Many make the pilgrimage to the stone circle every summer and winter and consider it a spiritual experience.
The ancient...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/945907eb-e8b8-4086-842e-b15d4daeaa9e_8c84218a.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Maduro condemns attacks on tankers carrying Venezuelan oil</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062763</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062763</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:05:51 +0000</pubDate><description>He noted that the Venezuelan people and all social strata of society remain steadfast in defending peace and national stability</description></item><item><title>US in pursuit of third tanker off coast of Venezuela — Bloomberg</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062755</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062755</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:51:49 +0000</pubDate><description>The reason is Donald Trump's tightening of the oil blockade against the government of Nicolas Maduro, noted Bloomberg</description></item><item><title>Nigerian government frees 130 kidnapped Catholic schoolchildren</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:53:26 +0000</pubDate><description>Nigerian authorities have secured the release of 130 kidnapped schoolchildren taken by gunmen from a Catholic school in November, a presidential spokesman said on Sunday, after 100 were freed earlier this month.
“Another 130 abducted Niger state pupils released, none left in captivity,” Sunday Dare said in a post on social media.
In late November, hundreds of pupils and staff were kidnapped from St Mary’s boarding school in north-central Niger state though the exact number and whether all are...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/97a37352-687c-42c1-ab81-c29a3500e5e8_a622b7ba.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>UK’s Starmer discusses Ukraine peace efforts in call with Trump</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:18:11 +0000</pubDate><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer discussed efforts to achieve a “just ‌and lasting end” to the war in Ukraine on Sunday with US President Donald Trump, Starmer’s Downing Street office said in a statement, after talks between officials in Florida.
“The two leaders began by reflecting ⁠on the war in Ukraine,” Starmer’s office said in a readout of the call, adding they had discussed the work of the so-called Coalition of the Willing countries that have pledged to support Ukraine.
“The Prime...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/7da60daf-1470-4b23-8368-3fe5bce75459_bd8a2294.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item>
      <title>Russia-Africa Forum agree plan of actions for 2026-2029 — top Egyptian diplomat</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062509</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062509</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to Badr Abdelatty, Russia and African countries agreed to "develop relations and hold political consultations on the basis of the norms of international law and the principle of non-interference into countries’ domestic affairs"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, Qatar, Egypt, Turkey report progress in implementing Gaza ceasefire phase one</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062515</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062515</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>As follows from the document, they held talks in Miami, Florida</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyz president arrives in Russia on working visit</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062519</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062519</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Sadyr Japarov has arrived to take part in the meeting of the Supreme Eurasian Economic Council and the informal meeting of CIS leaders in St. Petersburg, the press service of the Kyrgyz leader said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aggression against Venezuela may lead to humanitarian catastrophe — Brazilian leader</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062521</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062521</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva called on the countries of the region to consolidate their efforts to preserve it as a zone of peace and stability</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Egyptian diplomat describes Miami talks on Gaza as good</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062523</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062523</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Egyptian Foreign Minister Badr Abdelatty also expressed hope for the soonest beginning of the implementation of the Gaza deal second phase</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky admits that Kiev will not be able to finance 800,000-strong army</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062527</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062527</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Zelensky said that he maintains dialogue with Western leaders concerning partial financing of Ukrainian army at the expense of the partners</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US department confirms detention of tanker near Venezuelan coast</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062533</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062533</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"The United States will continue to pursue the illicit movement of sanctioned oil," the Head of the Department of Homeland Security Kristi Noem said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanker apprehended by the US near Venezuela sailed under flag of Panama — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062535</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062535</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the newspaper, the cargo belonged to an oil trader from China that supplies oil from Venezuela to Chinese refineries</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz finds himself in isolation in Europe due to position on Russian assets — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062545</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062545</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>German Chancellor attempted till the last "to praise advantages of the de facto expropriation of Russian assets, downplaying risks at the same time," the newspaper said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US National Intelligence confident Russia not planning to control entire Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062553</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062553</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard called such information about Russia's plans "a lie and propaganda"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump at ‘risk of becoming the deep state’ after Epstein file omissions</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Extensive redactions and the limited number of documents released related to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein angered some Republicans and did little to defuse a scandal threatening the party ahead of the 2026 midterm election.
The Trump administration touted this week’s release of a cache of Epstein-related files as a show of transparency, but a handful of Republican lawmakers and right-wing media figures joined Democrats in ‍blasting Friday’s disclosures as inadequate and possibly in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/ea215dd0-b670-4b62-93dc-10d73ab67e6d_e6860d97.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some US lawmakers capitalize on Ukrainian conflict — US Representative</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062555</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062555</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Representative Anna Paulina Luna noted that some lawmakers openly speak against efforts to settle the conflict in Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Representative Luna says not supporting money allocation to Kiev</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062557</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062557</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Anna Paulina Luna stressed that she "never voted for a single dollar to go to Ukraine"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan government condemns tanker capture by the US</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062559</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062559</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the government communique, this "egregiously criminal act" was made in violation of norms of international law, the maritime navigation convention and the UN Charter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep State wants military conflict between the US and Russia, Gabbard says</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062563</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062563</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said that every time Donald Trump makes progress and moves closer and closer to that hope for peace, the warmongers in the deep state step up and try to do everything they can to stop it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says Putin open to Ukraine war talks with France’s Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Putin is ready to talk to France’s Emmanuel Macron over the war in Ukraine, the Russian president’s spokesman said in an interview published on Sunday.
Putin has “expressed readiness to engage in dialogue with Macron”, Dmitry Peskov told state news agency RIA Novosti.
“Therefore, if there is mutual political will, then this can only be assessed positively.”
Macron said this week he believed Europe should reach back out to Putin over ending the war.
“I believe that it’s in our interest...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/3723c012-0f7d-457f-94eb-987e61098f5a_9b32b615.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive San Francisco power outage leaves thousands in the dark</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A huge electricity outage hit San Francisco on Saturday, leaving 130,000 residents without power and prompting city authorities to ask residents to stay home, according to the utility provider and the mayor.
Large parts of the west coast tech hub, which has a population of more than 800,000 people, were plunged into darkness with disruptions to public transport and many traffic lights not working on a busy Christmas shopping weekend.
“We are working with first responders and city officials on an...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/b3185e4f-b90c-4ace-836c-bcf49b3f87bb_2a29557f.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi Arabia’s discreet alcohol store opens doors to wealthy foreigners</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Saudi Arabia has quietly expanded access to its only store that sells alcohol, allowing wealthy foreign residents to buy booze in the latest step in the once-ultraconservative kingdom’s experiment in liberalisation.
There has been no official announcement of the decision, but word has got out, and long queues of cars and people can now be seen at the discreet, unmarked store in the Diplomatic Quarter of the Saudi capital, Riyadh.
The store opened in January 2024 for non-Muslim diplomats. The new...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/a53c9a65-a957-43f7-ae3a-2952e1b81149_cdd80239.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand doesn’t rule out possibility of a ceasefire in conflict zone with Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062595</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062595</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A special meeting of ASEAN foreign ministers was initiated by Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim and will be held on December 22 in Kuala Lumpur</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South African gun violence kills 9, wounds 10 in pub shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Nine people have died and at least 10 others were wounded after a group of gunmen carried out a shooting at a South African pub during the early hours of Sunday, authorities said.
The incident occurred just before 1am in the township of Bekkersdal, which is located 46 kilometres (28 miles) west of Johannesburg. It is the second mass shooting to happen in South Africa in three weeks.
About 12 unknown suspects in a white minibus and a silver sedan opened fire at pub patrons at KwaNoxolo tavern, in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/0cd9d4b0-dccd-4236-83fb-1f764b3afde1_9e0ef332.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron, on UAE visit, announces new French aircraft carrier</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>French President Emmanuel Macron said on Sunday he had given the official go-ahead to replace his country’s flagship, the nuclear-powered Charles de Gaulle aircraft carrier.
That vessel, the only nuclear-powered carrier outside the US Navy, entered service in 2001 following more than a decade of construction.
“In line with the last two military programming laws, and after a thorough and comprehensive review, I have decided to equip France with a new aircraft carrier,” Macron said, speaking...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/3c0cd7c3-6ab4-4d9e-a531-ca29d4a26132_3ced8932.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump tariffs push Swiss pharma CEO to urge price alignment with US</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Roche’s Chief Executive an interview with Swiss media published on Sunday called for Switzerland to pay more for new drugs, to bring prices in line with those paid by Washington.
The Swiss pharmaceutical giant’s US subsidiary Genentech figures among 14 pharmaceutical companies which have so far signed on to US President Donald Trump’s push to cut some US drug prices.
Companies have been making these voluntary deals after Trump sent a letter to 17 major companies over the summer threatening...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/076e200f-c771-4230-b4b2-eeeec1c81cd7_48271cc2.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lukashenko says Belarus and Russia implement all agreements, almost no questions exist</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062675</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062675</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Lukashenko also thanked Putin for evaluating his speech at the session of the All-Belarusian National Assembly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron betrays Merz on expropriation of frozen Russian assets — FT</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062677</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062677</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"He knows that there will be a price to pay for that", also said a senior EU diplomat</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building cooperation with third countries important for EAEU — Lukashenko</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062679</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062679</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Minsk fully supports the search for new partners from among the states of the global majority, moving to those regions of the world where the EAEU nations are respected and expected</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war drags on as drone attack kills 10 in Darfur market</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A drone attack on a busy market in Sudan’s North Darfur state killed 10 people over the weekend, first responders said, without saying who was responsible.
The attack comes as fighting intensified elsewhere in the country, leading aid workers to be evacuated on Sunday from Kadugli, a besieged, famine-hit city in the south.
Since April 2023, Sudan’s army and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces have been locked in a conflict, which has killed tens of thousands of people, displaced nearly 12...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/16475f84-5b77-4521-a340-f76ad3453332_a7a87b60.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US is pursuing a third oil tanker near Venezuela, officials say</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>The US Coast Guard is pursuing ‌an oil tanker in international waters near Venezuela, officials told Reuters ‍on Sunday, in what would be the second such operation this weekend and the third in less than a week.
One of the officials said the tanker was under sanctions.
The ⁠officials, who were speaking on condition of anonymity, did not give a specific location for the operation.
The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday. US President Donald Trump last week...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/f95b4396-7c43-407c-8cfe-50c49719b007_098a8778.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elysee Palace silver steward arrested for stealing silverware worth up to US$47,000</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Three men will stand trial next year after a silver steward employed at the official residence of the French president was arrested this week for the theft of items of silverware and table service worth thousands of euros, the Paris prosecutor’s office said.
The Elysee Palace’s head steward reported the disappearance, with the estimated loss ranging between €15,000 and €40,000 (US$17,500-US$47,000).
The Sevres Manufactory – which supplied most of the furnishings – identified several of the...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/66a17c5b-5717-443e-ab09-2c426ac677c8_9060a565.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top US official defends partial release of Epstein files as Democrats cry foul</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche on Sunday defended the Justice Department’s decision to release just a fraction of the Jeffrey Epstein files by the congressionally mandated deadline as necessary to protect survivors of sexual abuse by the disgraced financier.
Blanche pledged that the Trump administration eventually would meet its obligation required by law. However, he stressed that the department was obliged to act with caution as it goes about making public thousands of documents that...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/798bb936-94b8-4a92-a046-75a3ff708947_ad4d6e25.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <title>World News Unified Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.theguardian.com</link>
    <description>Merged World News RSS</description>
  </channel>
</rss>
