<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <item><title>Inside Chernobyl: Ukraine races to repair radiation shield as war drags on</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337774/inside-chernobyl-ukraine-races-repair-radiation-shield-war-drags?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337774/inside-chernobyl-ukraine-races-repair-radiation-shield-war-drags?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 04:50:42 +0000</pubDate><description>Inside an abandoned control room at Ukraine’s Chernobyl nuclear power plant, a worker in an orange hard hat gazed at a grey wall of seemingly endless dials, screens and gauges that were supposed to prevent disaster.
The 1986 meltdown at the site was the world’s worst ever nuclear incident. Since Russia invaded in 2022, Kyiv fears another disaster could be just a matter of time.
In February, a Russian drone hit and left a large hole in the New Safe Confinement (NSC), the outer of two radiation...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/26/a539d969-6550-43a9-8d4d-775a444fdb25_be403cc9.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>China ready to strengthen international arms control system — embassy in US</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064963</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064963</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:17:24 +0000</pubDate><description>Spokesperson Liu Pengyu emphasized that China has always adhered to the path of peaceful development</description></item><item><title>US forces conduct strike against IS militants in Nigeria — Trump</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064969</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064969</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:25:08 +0000</pubDate><description>Pentagon Chief Pete Hegseth expressed gratitude to the Nigerian authorities, stating that he was "grateful for Nigerian government support &amp; cooperation"</description></item><item><title>Arms supplies to Taiwan to bring US no closer to its goals — Chinese embassy</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064971</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064971</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:27:59 +0000</pubDate><description>Such moves will not reverse the inevitable failure of Taiwan independence, spokesperson Liu Pengyu stated</description></item><item><title>DPRK announces death of senior official Kim Chang Son</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064973</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064973</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:51:52 +0000</pubDate><description>The KCNA stated that he long occupied important party and state positions</description></item><item><title>Bundeswehr should take part in peacekeeping in Ukraine under European flag — EU politician</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064975</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064975</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 01:20:18 +0000</pubDate><description>The head of the conservative European People’s Party Manfred Weber asserted that US President Donald Trump will not "ensure a peaceful settlement exclusively with US troops"</description></item><item><title>British police to request data from FBI on possible crimes by former Prince Andrew</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064981</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064981</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate><description>The former duke stepped down from his royal duties in 2019 after denying allegations of sexually assaulting a teenage Virginia Giuffre</description></item><item><title>Trump threatens Democrats with "last Christmas" in light of Epstein case</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064985</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064985</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:39:08 +0000</pubDate><description>The US leader also noted that Democrats will "have a lot of explaining to do" when their involvement in US financier scandal becomes known</description></item><item><title>US launched ‘deadly’ strikes against Isis in Nigeria, Trump says</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337749/us-launches-strikes-against-isis-nigeria-trump-says?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337749/us-launches-strikes-against-isis-nigeria-trump-says?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:37:30 +0000</pubDate><description>The United States ‌carried out air strikes against ‍Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria, US President Donald Trump ⁠said on Thursday, claiming the group had been targeting Christians in ‍the region.
“Tonight, at my ‍direction as Commander in Chief, the ‌United States launched a powerful and ‍deadly strike against ISIS Terrorist Scum in Northwest Nigeria, who ‌have been ⁠targeting and viciously killing, primarily, innocent Christians, at levels not seen for ‌many years, and even...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/26/137efcb0-15df-4549-a8d5-2dfbc83dff10_1741b27e.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>King Charles calls for ‘reconciliation’ in Christmas speech</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337748/king-charles-calls-reconciliation-christmas-speech?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337748/king-charles-calls-reconciliation-christmas-speech?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:05:05 +0000</pubDate><description>Britain’s King Charles called for “compassion and reconciliation” at a time of “division” across the world in his Christmas Day message on Thursday.
The 77-year-old monarch said he found it “enormously encouraging” how people of different faiths had a “shared longing for peace”.
Charles praised individuals who risked their lives to save others in situations of violence, including those caught up in the killings at a Jewish event at Bondi Beach in Australia this month.
“Individuals and...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/26/c8ba3376-38ee-4b62-97b2-1aff76d56bc7_d4c096d9.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Venezuela grateful to Russia for support in defending its sovereignty — foreign minister</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064961</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064961</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:06:46 +0000</pubDate><description>Yvan Gil Pinto highly appreciated Russia’ "steadfast support" in preserving a zone of peace in the Caribbean</description></item><item><title>US ready to facilitate peace talks between Cambodia, Thailand — Rubio</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064959</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064959</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 22:32:32 +0000</pubDate><description>US Secretary of State spoke with Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manet to "express concern about the ongoing violence between Cambodia and Thailand"</description></item><item><title>First meeting of working group on elections to be held in Ukraine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064953</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064953</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:51:45 +0000</pubDate><description>First Deputy Chairman of the Verkhovna Rada, head of the "Servant of the People" party, Alexander Korniyenko announced it</description></item><item><title>Two militant bases dismantled in CAR, plans to disrupt presidential elections thwarted</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064957</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064957</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 22:14:44 +0000</pubDate><description>One base housing about 30 militants was uncovered 50 km south of the Auk settlement, they retreated into Chad</description></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel takes aim at Trump in ‘alternative Christmas message’ to UK</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337747/jimmy-kimmel-takes-aim-trump-alternative-christmas-message-uk?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337747/jimmy-kimmel-takes-aim-trump-alternative-christmas-message-uk?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:43:24 +0000</pubDate><description>Talk show host Jimmy Kimmel took aim at US President Donald Trump as he warned on Thursday about the rise of fascism in an address to UK viewers dubbed “The Alternative Christmas Message.”
The message, aired on Channel 4 on Christmas Day, reflected on the impact from the second term in office for Trump, who Kimmel said acts like he is a king.
“From a fascism perspective, this has been a really great year,” he said. “Tyranny is booming over here.”
The channel began a tradition of airing an...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/26/36256b64-28f2-43a0-bc1e-6f51f11c3f1c_a14e9028.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Bundestag believes German army has opportunity to ensure peace in Ukraine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064949</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064949</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:38:18 +0000</pubDate><description>head of the Bundestag defense committee Thomas Rowekamp said that the German army "has capabilities that it can use, including in Ukraine"</description></item><item><title>Germany to have to return to compulsory military draft — paper</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064933</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064933</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 19:58:59 +0000</pubDate><description>Head of the Bundestag defense committee Thomas Rowekamp said that 20,000-30,000 servicemen leave the active army every year</description></item><item><title>Ukraine has no money to hold elections — Zelensky's office</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064941</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064941</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:29:58 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Mikhail Podolyak, Ukraine’s budget has other priority expenditures, including militarization</description></item><item><title>Iranian special forces officer eliminated in Lebanon — IDF</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064913</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064913</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:58:51 +0000</pubDate><description>Spokesman Avichay Adraee said Hussein al-Jawhari had led operations against Israel in Syria and Lebanon in recent years</description></item><item><title>Brazil’s Bolsonaro backs son’s residential bid, undergoes hernia surgery</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337746/brazils-bolsonaro-backs-sons-residential-bid-undergoes-hernia-surgery?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337746/brazils-bolsonaro-backs-sons-residential-bid-undergoes-hernia-surgery?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate><description>Brazil’s former president Jair Bolsonaro endorsed his son ‌Flavio’s 2026 presidential bid on Thursday in a statement from a hospital where he ‍underwent a scheduled hernia operation that doctors said went smoothly.
Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes authorised Bolsonaro to leave prison, where he is serving a 27-year sentence for plotting a coup, for the surgery. Police were ordered to stay outside ⁠his room where computers and mobile phones were prohibited.
Senator Flavio Bolsonaro, 44,...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/26/5b722544-c9c8-4215-9733-da0741d5ca6a_c96a3f09.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>French politician sides with Telegram founder, accuses Macron of creating 'digital gulag'</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064903</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064903</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:26:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Florian Philippot also called for France to leave the European Union as soon as possible in order to protect freedom of speech</description></item><item><title>Conclusions on causes of AZAL plane crash to be presented in final report</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064883</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064883</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:32:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Currently, the commission is waiting for the results of the examination of the central maintenance computer cassette and the completion of a report from the working group responsible for analyzing risk assessments related to flights over or near conflict zones</description></item><item><title>Niger bans issuing visas to US citizens — agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064895</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064895</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:54:59 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the sources, the measure is based on the principle of reciprocity</description></item><item><title>Zelensky says he spoke with Witkoff and Kushner by telephone</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064899</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064899</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:05:25 +0000</pubDate><description>Vladimir Zelensky did not disclose the content of the conversation</description></item><item><title>Russia makes ‘proposal’ to France over jailed NGO researcher Vinatier</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337745/russia-makes-proposal-france-over-jailed-ngo-researcher-vinatier?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337745/russia-makes-proposal-france-over-jailed-ngo-researcher-vinatier?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate><description>Moscow has made an offer to Paris regarding jailed French researcher Laurent Vinatier, who is facing espionage charges that could see him sentenced to 20 years in a Russian prison, the Kremlin said on Thursday.
The surprise public overture comes as both Russia and France have expressed interest in possible talks between Presidents Vladimir Putin and Emmanuel Macron.
Vinatier, who works for a Swiss conflict mediation NGO and was jailed in June 2024, is serving a three-year sentence for failing to...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/02b612d7-9224-4124-8479-a3e00a6ab323_6cdcc752.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Andrew’s daughters join UK royals for traditional Christmas Day service</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337744/andrews-daughters-join-uk-royals-traditional-christmas-day-service?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337744/andrews-daughters-join-uk-royals-traditional-christmas-day-service?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate><description>Britain’s Princesses Beatrice and Eugenie attended the royal family’s traditional Christmas Day church service ‌on Thursday, while their father Andrew, recently stripped of his titles ‍over ties to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, was absent.
King Charles and Queen Camilla led senior royals to a church in Sandringham in eastern England, about 110 miles (175 km) northeast of ⁠London, greeting well-wishers in crisp winter weather.
Charles and Camilla walked ahead while the Prince and...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/6fa952ca-c7fa-4d0f-85fc-1a51e3ddecf8_40622490.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>‘Christmas under fire’: Ukraine, Russia report fatal air strikes</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337736/christmas-under-fire-ukraine-russia-report-fatal-air-strikes?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337736/christmas-under-fire-ukraine-russia-report-fatal-air-strikes?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:07:44 +0000</pubDate><description>Russian air attacks caused death and destruction across Ukraine, authorities in different regions reported on Thursday, with Russian authorities reporting similar Ukrainian attacks on their territory.
A Russian drone attack in the southwestern Odesa region on the Black Sea left one person dead and two injured. Damage was caused to port and energy infrastructure, the regional authorities said.
In the Kharkiv region bordering Russia in Ukraine’s northeast, one person died and 15 were injured.
And...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/ea1beedf-26c5-4148-b88c-b3274255b04f_1485991c.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Zelensky’s idea of putting his peace plan to a referendum against the law, ex-MP says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064719</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064719</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:22:02 +0000</pubDate><description>"Zelensky cannot put any issue to a referendum, and he has an exclusive list of what he can actually put," Nikolay Tomenko said</description></item><item><title>Japan using conflict with China as pretext for its nuclear ambitions — defense ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064665</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064665</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:47:50 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Chinese Defense Ministry Spokesman Zhang Xiaogang, Japanese right-wing forces have finally "dropped the mask of hypocrisy" and are now openly advocating for nuclear weapons, which poses a direct challenge to the post-war world order</description></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia hopes separatists will leave captured Yemeni provinces — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064673</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064673</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:50:42 +0000</pubDate><description>The kingdom called on all Yemeni forces to cooperate, exercise restraint and avoid any steps that could destabilize the situation</description></item><item><title>Beijing opposes US maritime blockade of Venezuela</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064687</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064687</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:20:19 +0000</pubDate><description>According to He Yongqian, Beijing believes that a US blockade "could not only disrupt the normal functioning of international energy markets, but also pose additional security risks"</description></item><item><title>Israeli forces conduct raids across villages of Quneitra province in southern Syria</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064651</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064651</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:31:07 +0000</pubDate><description>Al Mayadeen said Israeli occupation forces are reinforcing their military base in Tal Ahmar, where additional troops have been deployed and prefabricated housing units delivered for personnel</description></item><item><title>Trump administration achieves record decrease in murders in one year — FBI director</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064587</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064587</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:33:36 +0000</pubDate><description>The number of mass murders in the country has also fallen to its lowest level since 2006</description></item><item><title>Chinese army strenghtens dialogue with Russia, US, EU in 2025 — top brass</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064553</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064553</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:51:56 +0000</pubDate><description>Chinese Defense Ministry Spokesman Zhang Xiaogang recalled that in 2025, a delegation from the Chinese Central Military Commission had visited Russia</description></item><item><title>Trump wishes merry Christmas to all, including 'radical left scum'</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064465</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064465</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:39:36 +0000</pubDate><description>Speaking of his administration’s achievements, the US president pointed out that the US no longer had "open borders, men in women’s sports, transgender for everyone, or weak law enforcement"</description></item><item><title>Conflict with Thailand leaves over 630,000 Cambodians dispaced — ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064469</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064469</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:05:15 +0000</pubDate><description>The latest data from Cambodia's National Defense Ministry indicates that 31 civilians were killed and at least 87 others were injured as a result of shelling</description></item><item><title>DPRK to respond in kind to US 'nuclear muscle flexing' in South Korea</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064479</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064479</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:25:13 +0000</pubDate><description>The DPRK’s defense ministry denounced the US submarine's port call in Busan as a "grave act of causing instability and escalating military tensions in the Korean peninsula and the region"</description></item><item><title>The Pentagon seeks to sow discord in China's relations with other countries — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064481</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064481</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:38:20 +0000</pubDate><description>Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesman Lin Jian condemned Washington's interference in China's bilateral relations, stating that the Chinese Foreign Ministry strongly protests against such actions and calls on the United States to cease spreading false narratives</description></item><item><title>Zelensky's desire to maintain army size proves he is not thinking about peace — politician</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064491</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064491</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:44:06 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the former Ukrainian PM, it was already a "big problem" for Ukraine to maintain an army of up to 180,000 servicemen before the conflict</description></item><item><title>Anonymous Japanese official who broke nation's 'nuclear taboo' unveiled</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064537</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064537</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate><description>Japan adheres to three non-nuclear principles not to possess, develop or allow nuclear weapons into its territory</description></item><item><title>Afghanistan not doing enough to ensure border security — Tajikistan</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064539</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064539</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate><description>Tajikistan’s border troops said hopefully the Taliban will apologize to the Tajik people and take "additional effective measures" to secure the border</description></item><item><title>Pentagon’s report distorts reality of Chinese military developments — newspaper</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064441</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064441</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:08:49 +0000</pubDate><description>The newspaper emphasizes that "it is crucial for China and the US to accurately understand each other's strategic intentions through dialogue"</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian city of Odessa reports partial power cuts</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064437</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064437</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:10:17 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the DTEK energy company, an accident occurred in the morning at another company’s energy facility</description></item><item><title>Japan’s chief cabinet secretary refrains from comments on MP’s visit to Russia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064431</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064431</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:02:18 +0000</pubDate><description>Muneo Suzuki, a member of the Japanese parliament’s upper chamber from the ruling Liberal Democratic Party of Japan, departed to Russia on a visit earlier in the day</description></item><item><title>Ukraine’s ex-premier describes Zelensky’s plan as attempt to stall talks</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064419</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064419</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 03:15:06 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Nikolay Azarov, the plan does not resolve a number of important issues</description></item><item><title>MP from Japan’s ruling party, Muneo Suzuki, departs to Russia on visit</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064421</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064421</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 03:41:11 +0000</pubDate><description>He is expected to meet with a number of Russian officials</description></item><item><title>Southern California drenched by powerful Christmas storms, flash flooding</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337681/southern-california-drenched-powerful-christmas-storms-flash-flooding?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337681/southern-california-drenched-powerful-christmas-storms-flash-flooding?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 03:35:18 +0000</pubDate><description>Flash flood warnings were in effect in Los Angeles and most of southern California on Wednesday as one of the worst Christmas storms in recent memory brought heavy rain and fears of deadly mudslides.
Driven by an atmospheric river known as “the Pineapple Express”, which moves heavy moisture from the tropical climes of Hawaii to rain on the West Coast, the storm is expected to deliver months’ worth of rain over the next few days.
California Governor Gavin Newsom declared a state of emergency in...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/c38421fa-bbbd-4561-aa2f-8280b07c82d9_1bf1d6d8.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US Department of Justice gets more documents as part of Epstein case files</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064385</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064385</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:53:08 +0000</pubDate><description>Their release may take a few more weeks</description></item><item><title>Refusal to take path of peace is Ukraine’s tragedy — German general</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064387</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064387</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:11:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Harald Kujat opined that the West’s massive support created an illusion for Kiev that "it can turn the strategic situation into its favor"</description></item><item><title>Honduras election authority says Trump-backed candidate won presidential election</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064393</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064393</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:57:53 +0000</pubDate><description>Nasry Juan Asfura Zablah received 40.27% of the vote</description></item><item><title>Conflict in Ukraine can be resolved within 90 days — US envoy to NATO</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064399</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064399</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 01:17:27 +0000</pubDate><description>Matthew Whittaker noted that the forthcoming winter may be very difficult for Ukraine</description></item><item><title>Polish officials not allowed to enter Russian consulate’s former building</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064413</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064413</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 02:26:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Poland’s last operating Russian Consulate General located in the city of Gdansk closed down earlier this week</description></item><item><title>Pope Leo celebrates first Christmas as pontiff</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337672/pope-leo-celebrates-first-christmas-pontiff?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337672/pope-leo-celebrates-first-christmas-pontiff?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:56:39 +0000</pubDate><description>Pope Leo held the first Christmas mass of his pontificate on Wednesday, greeting thousands of faithful in St Peter’s Square before the service.
During the mass, Leo said Christmas was a feast of “faith, charity and hope” and criticised a “distorted economy” that “leads us to treat human beings as mere merchandise”.
Before, he spoke in front of St Peter’s Basilica to offer Christmas wishes and thank those who had come to follow the mass on outdoor screens despite rainy weather.
“St Peter’s is...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/093fafee-aeb3-4860-a47e-5c07dc5e97f3_5ff76fc0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukraine unable to keep 800,000-strong army — German general</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064365</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064365</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 22:05:01 +0000</pubDate><description>Harald Kujat noted that the 800,000-strong Ukrainian army, as required by the Europeans, would constitute a significant increase from the pre-conflict number</description></item><item><title>Trump-backed Nasry Asfura declared winner of Honduras presidential election</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337671/trump-backed-nasry-asfura-declared-winner-honduras-presidential-election?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337671/trump-backed-nasry-asfura-declared-winner-honduras-presidential-election?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:56:36 +0000</pubDate><description>Trump-backed candidate Nasry Asfura won Honduras’ presidential election, the country’s electoral authorities said on Wednesday afternoon, ending a weeks-long count that has whittled away at the credibility of the Central American nation’s fragile electoral system.
The election is continuing Latin America’s swing to the right, coming just a week after Chile chose the far-right politician Jose Antonio Kast as its next president.
Asfura, of the conservative National Party, received 40.27 per cent...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/2492837c-340d-49e0-a612-c74e7496477f_512c2cca.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US believes sides approaching settlement on Ukraine — NATO envoy</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064353</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064353</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:52:01 +0000</pubDate><description>US Permanent Representative to NATO Matthew Whitaker emphasized that there are still matters that need to be resolved in a way that both sides can agree</description></item><item><title>US to maintain naval blockade of Venezuela for at least two months — Reuters</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064355</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064355</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate><description>The White House has ordered American forces in the region to focus almost exclusively "on the quarantine of Venezuelan oil"</description></item><item><title>US has mostly resolved security issues with Ukrainians — NATO envoy</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064359</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064359</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate><description>"It’s going to come down to, ultimately, the territory, and how that territory is divided up," Matthew Whitaker said</description></item><item><title>After missing Epstein files deadline, Trump admin says it may need ‘few more weeks’</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337670/after-missing-epstein-files-deadline-trump-admin-says-it-may-need-few-more-weeks?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337670/after-missing-epstein-files-deadline-trump-admin-says-it-may-need-few-more-weeks?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:20:18 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Justice Department said Wednesday that it may need a “few more weeks” to release all of its records on the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein after suddenly discovering more than a million potentially relevant documents, further delaying compliance with last Friday’s congressionally mandated deadline.
The Christmas Eve announcement came hours after a dozen US senators called on the Justice Department’s watchdog to examine its failure to meet the deadline.
The group, 11 Democrats and a...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/129b8462-55db-4522-8ae7-0895400eecfa_0b4bade8.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Moldovan border guards cut off channel for transfer of draft dodgers from Ukraine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064349</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064349</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:36:01 +0000</pubDate><description>The police said the suspects charged each evader $10,000</description></item><item><title>Italian expert says Zelensky's new peace plan step in wrong direction</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064335</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064335</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate><description>Ukraine has submitted the 20-point peace plan, which, according to Kiev, should consolidate the country's security, attract international assistance and establish long-term guarantees from NATO and the EU</description></item><item><title>Hamas informs Turkey about Israel's violations of Gaza agreement</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064337</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064337</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Head of the group Khalil al-Hayy also drew attention to the "deteriorating humanitarian crisis" in the Gaza Strip</description></item><item><title>Belgium shocked by US sanctions against five EU citizens — foreign minister</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064327</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064327</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:30 +0000</pubDate><description>Maxime Prevot said that EU digital legislation is not directed against the United States, but serves to ensure that EU citizens have the same security and dignity in the digital space that they enjoy in their public lives in Europe</description></item><item><title>EU loan will not lead to improvement in Ukrainian military’s situation — Guardian</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064323</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064323</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:49:12 +0000</pubDate><description>The Guardian draws attention to the low level of recruitment into the Ukrainian armed forces</description></item><item><title>French president, NATO chief discuss Ukraine-related efforts by Coalition of Willing</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064299</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064299</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:59:32 +0000</pubDate><description>The previous meeting of the so-called Coalition of the Willing took place on December 11</description></item><item><title>Trump says comedian Colbert should be ‘put to sleep’</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337669/trump-says-comedian-colbert-should-be-put-sleep?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337669/trump-says-comedian-colbert-should-be-put-sleep?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:16:24 +0000</pubDate><description>Just before Christmas, US President Donald Trump has unleashed a fresh blast of vitriol at late-night comedy talk shows, saying comedian Stephen Colbert is a “pathetic train wreck” who should be “put to sleep”.
Colbert’s The Late Show is scheduled to end in May 2026, a decision his fans say smacks of censorship.
In a late-night social media post, Trump said that Colbert “has actually gotten worse” since being “terminated by CBS, but left out to dry”.
“Stephen is running on hatred and fumes – A...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/e6106cc9-bb62-4ddd-9bd1-c4c7d91fe37e_ad60a982.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>This winter to be most difficult in Ukraine since February 2022 — energy provider CEO</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064229</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064229</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:20:15 +0000</pubDate><description>Maxim Timchenko emphasized that since September, over 50% of the holding’s generation capacity has been damaged or destroyed</description></item><item><title>West needs Zelensky's peace plan to pump resources out of Ukraine — expert</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064245</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064245</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:52:55 +0000</pubDate><description>The clause on creating special funds to attract $800 billion for Ukraine's reconstruction was introduced "because money can be made on creating these funds," Alexander Dudchak said</description></item><item><title>Israel denies Palestinian vice president entry to Bethlehem</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064255</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064255</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:31:44 +0000</pubDate><description>No reason was given as to why Hussein al-Sheikh was denied entry to Bethlehem</description></item><item><title>Foreign intelligence services monitoring Oreshnik missile deployment in Belarus — KGB</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064257</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064257</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:33:28 +0000</pubDate><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko earlier stated that a maximum of 10 Russian-made Oreshnik systems would be deployed in the republic</description></item><item><title>Several points of Zelensky’s so-called plan unworkable, expert says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064261</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064261</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:55:57 +0000</pubDate><description>Alexander Dudchak doubts that Kiev is really ready to carry out an "all-for-all" prisoner swap according to the plan</description></item><item><title>Japanese lawmaker, stalwart Moscow supporter Suzuki plans to visit Russia soon — agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064267</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064267</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:11:24 +0000</pubDate><description>Muneo Suzuki is expected to meet with Russian officials during the visit</description></item><item><title>Syrian Interior Ministry says Kurdish fighters stop civilians from leaving Aleppo</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064275</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064275</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:21:10 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the statement, the transitional government's security forces "continue to fulfill their national responsibilities, taking strict measures aimed at protecting civilians"</description></item><item><title>UN experts call on US Congress to intervene to stop aggression against Venezuela</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064277</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064277</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:21:55 +0000</pubDate><description>In their view, the blockade of oil tankers going into, and out of, Venezuela violates "fundamental rules of international law"</description></item><item><title>US sanctions against former European officials cast doubt on EU sovereignty — Kallas</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064281</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064281</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:24:18 +0000</pubDate><description>The chief of the European diplomacy said that Europe will continue to defend its values of freedom of expression</description></item><item><title>Bethlehem celebrates first festive Christmas since Gaza war</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337668/bethlehem-celebrates-first-festive-christmas-gaza-war?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337668/bethlehem-celebrates-first-festive-christmas-gaza-war?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:03:58 +0000</pubDate><description>Thousands of people flocked to Bethlehem’s Manger Square on Christmas Eve as families heralded a much-needed boost of holiday spirit. The giant Christmas tree that was absent during the Israel-Gaza war returned on Wednesday.
The city where Christians believe Jesus was born had cancelled Christmas celebrations for the past two years. Manger Square instead had featured a nativity scene of baby Jesus surrounded by rubble and barbed wire in homage to the situation in Gaza.
Cardinal Pierbattista...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/25/4917705c-acae-4d1b-86f5-f780bd709ce3_2ab0df74.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Trump vs EU: the European laws curbing big tech and irking US president</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337663/trump-vs-eu-european-laws-curbing-big-tech-and-irking-us-president?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337663/trump-vs-eu-european-laws-curbing-big-tech-and-irking-us-president?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate><description>The European Union is back in the crosshairs of the Trump administration over its tech rules, which Washington denounced as an attempt to “coerce” American social media platforms into censoring viewpoints they oppose.
The US State Department said on Tuesday it would deny visas to a former EU commissioner and four others, saying they “have advanced censorship crackdowns by foreign states – in each case targeting American speakers and American companies”.
Trump has vowed to punish countries that...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/dd71a7b6-3723-41d2-bf41-71e0d70dfd07_ad3ec216.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Algeria brands French colonisation a crime, demands reparations, apology in landmark move</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337664/algeria-brands-french-colonisation-crime-demands-apology-reparations-landmark-move?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337664/algeria-brands-french-colonisation-crime-demands-apology-reparations-landmark-move?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:08:45 +0000</pubDate><description>Algeria’s parliament unanimously approved on Wednesday a law declaring France’s colonisation of the country a crime, and demanding an apology and reparations.
Standing in the chamber, lawmakers wearing scarves in the colours of the national flag chanted “long live Algeria” as they applauded the passage of the bill, which said France held “legal responsibility for its colonial past in Algeria and the tragedies it caused”.
The vote comes as the two countries are embroiled in a major diplomatic...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/aae0e5c2-5ba7-4e3b-bd72-599694d5a866_325306f3.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Europe has 'epiphany' on Ukraine negotiations — opposition figure</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064223</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064223</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Medvedchuk said that Europe had previously acted as a "bridge between Russia and the United States," but today's attempts by Europeans to build a wall between Moscow and Washington "are a joke"</description></item><item><title>West tries to sweeten bitter pill for Ukraine promising it admission to EU — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064213</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064213</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:27:17 +0000</pubDate><description>The Hungarian Prime Minister stressed that Budapest openly opposed the talks on bringing Ukraine into the EU</description></item><item><title>Israel throws wrench in aid delivery process to Gaza again, Erdogan complains</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064215</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064215</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:28:37 +0000</pubDate><description>The Turkish president noted that with the onset of the cold weather and the onset of rains, the burden on Gazans has increased</description></item><item><title>UN Security Council extends mandate of African Union peacekeeping mission in Somalia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064217</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064217</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:30:17 +0000</pubDate><description>The main task of the peacekeepers in the area is to counter the radical Islamist group Al-Shabab and assist the Somali authorities in training their own security forces on counterterrorism</description></item><item><title>EU is militarizing Moldova despite its neutrality — Transnistrian Foreign Minister</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064219</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064219</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:38:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Vitaly Ignatiev said that the European Peace Fund is providing weapons and military equipment</description></item><item><title>Hungarian PM gives hot take on biggest threat of war facing Europe</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064211</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064211</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:21:16 +0000</pubDate><description>"The military tensions Europe is seeing now stem from the decline of Western Europe and the European Union," Viktor Orban said</description></item><item><title>US concerned Arab nations could refuse to cooperate on Gaza with Israel — reporter</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064195</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064195</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:40:56 +0000</pubDate><description>"The more Israel provokes, the less the Arab countries will want to work with them," the official said</description></item><item><title>EU got involved in conflict in Ukraine to rev up economy — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064177</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064177</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:02:53 +0000</pubDate><description>The prime minister believes the decision is wrong</description></item><item><title>European Union disintegrating before our eyes — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064183</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064183</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:15:20 +0000</pubDate><description>The Hungarian PM noted that "EU decision-makers are constantly forced to backtrack"</description></item><item><title>Another 25 children from Russia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Ukraine doxxed on ‘Mirotvorets’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064187</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064187</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:22:36 +0000</pubDate><description>All of them were born between 2017 and 2023</description></item><item><title>Belarus's opponents still hatch plots of regime change — state security committee KGB</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064141</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064141</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:08:57 +0000</pubDate><description>Ivan Tertel noted that foreign intelligence services were concentrating on areas Belarus views as key national interests or potential threats</description></item><item><title>EU had chance to prevent Russia conflict in 2022 — Hungarian PM</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064155</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064155</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:32:49 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban said that Europe could have sent a peace mission to Moscow and Kiev instead of declaring their conflict its own war</description></item><item><title>Ukraine’s major oil producer Ukrnafta sustains critical damage</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064159</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064159</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:33:17 +0000</pubDate><description>The company did not specify the exact nature of the damage or where it occurred</description></item><item><title>Trump’s US$100,000 H-1B visa fee upheld by judge, as lottery system ends</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337657/trumps-us100000-h-1b-visa-fee-upheld-judge-lottery-system-ends?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337657/trumps-us100000-h-1b-visa-fee-upheld-judge-lottery-system-ends?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:42:33 +0000</pubDate><description>A US federal judge on Tuesday upheld President Donald Trump’s US$100,000 fee to process H-1B visa applications, while also acknowledging it could “inflict significant harm on American businesses and institutions of higher education”.
In a 56-page opinion, US District Judge Beryl Howell wrote that the president has “broad statutory authority” to address “a problem he perceives to be a matter of economic and national security”.
The US$100,000 application fee announced in September gave companies...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/86595d86-f6d6-45ce-841e-ce17d5c10fce_027eee86.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Hungarian PM rings alarm bell on war</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064165</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064165</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban added that some proposals and decisions made at the European Union summit on December 18-19 were aimed at escalating the conflict in Ukraine and further antagonizing Russia</description></item><item><title>Active dialogue between Lukashenko, Trump proceeds — Minsk</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064107</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064107</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:18:56 +0000</pubDate><description>Such negotiations are traditionally conducted discreetly because "there are certain principles that must be observed to avoid jeopardizing the results we aim to achieve"</description></item><item><title>Latvia’s top diplomat bars 14 Russian athletes from entry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064111</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064111</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:20:13 +0000</pubDate><description>The imposed entry ban has no specific duration</description></item><item><title>Turkish president offers condolences to Libya over plane crash</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064115</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064115</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:22:54 +0000</pubDate><description>Libya’s Government of National Unity declared three days of mourning over the death of Libyan Army Chief of Staff Muhammad al-Haddad</description></item><item><title>Belarusian KGB sniffs out foreign spy ring eavesdropping on pilots — report</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064129</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064129</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate><description>The network was assisted by several individuals residing in Belarus</description></item><item><title>Belarusian leader receives report on Polonez-M rocket drills</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064073</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064073</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:31:46 +0000</pubDate><description>The report also touched upon the deployment of the Oreshnik missile system to Belarus and efforts to put it on combat duty</description></item><item><title>Chinese military stepping up its potential makes US more ‘vulnerable’ — Pentagon</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064021</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064021</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:58:39 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Pentagon, China continues to increase its nuclear potential and plans to acquire over 1,000 nuclear warheads by 2030</description></item><item><title>Thailand, Cambodia to hold talks on ceasefire at high level on December 27 — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064055</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064055</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate><description>From December 24 to 26, negotiations under this mechanism will take place at the secretariat level</description></item><item><title>Gloomy mood in European Commission’s headquarters — Politico</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064059</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064059</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:19:46 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the newspaper, after months of discussions, EU leaders "delivered a harsh reality check, with the executive’s ambitions dashed by political and national red lines"</description></item><item><title>US can gain control of Greenland without 'firing a shot' — EP member</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2064019</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2064019</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:56:09 +0000</pubDate><description>Anders Vistisen also noted that Denmark "cannot defend Greenland alone"</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian media outlet releases Kiev’s 20-point peace plan</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063985</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063985</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:13:48 +0000</pubDate><description>Ukraine presented this plan to the American side at recent talks in the United States</description></item><item><title>Black box from crashed Libyan plane found — Turkey’s interior minister</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063995</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063995</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:31:29 +0000</pubDate><description>The relief effort at the site of the crash involving 408 people is ongoing</description></item><item><title>Zelensky reveals US-backed 20-point peace plan and Ukraine land compromise deal for Putin</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337633/zelensky-reveals-us-backed-20-point-peace-plan-and-ukraine-land-compromise-deal-putin?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337633/zelensky-reveals-us-backed-20-point-peace-plan-and-ukraine-land-compromise-deal-putin?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:35:38 +0000</pubDate><description>Ukraine’s President Volodymyr Zelensky said the latest version of a plan to end the Russian invasion would freeze the front line, but still pave the way for Ukrainian withdrawals and the creation of demilitarised zones.
“We now have draft documents that largely reflect the joint Ukrainian-American position, in some respects the American position,” Zelensky told reporters in Kyiv on Tuesday. “Some issues are still to be resolved.”
Still, Zelensky offered an upbeat assessment, saying the...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/2934d860-52f5-4531-9cab-2b1f19b91723_d2573820.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Venezuela has overwhelming support in UN Security Council — president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063979</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063979</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 08:39:13 +0000</pubDate><description>The Venezuelan leader called the US seizure of vessels "piracy" and noted that "no one can defeat" the country</description></item><item><title>Top Syrian diplomat says country’s relations with Russia enter new stage</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063969</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063969</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 08:23:55 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Asaad al-Shaibani, Syria "seeks to forge balanced relations with all states"</description></item><item><title>BRICS has developed criteria for admitting new members — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063897</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063897</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate><description>A candidate country must have good relations with its neighbors and be opposed to unilateral sanctions, Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos noted</description></item><item><title>Emergence of BRICS payment system quite possible — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063895</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063895</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:48:58 +0000</pubDate><description>The diplomat called this topic one of the most important on the BRICS agenda</description></item><item><title>Brazil ready to cooperate with Russia on rare earth metals — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063901</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063901</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:55:04 +0000</pubDate><description>Brazil is open to dialogue with Russia, both in the area of extraction and production, and in the processing of these resources, Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos said</description></item><item><title>Thai F-16 fighter jets attack Cambodian territory — newspaper report</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063903</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063903</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:57:04 +0000</pubDate><description>Thai jets dropped six bombs near Phnom Sampov in the Banan district of the Battambang Province in northwestern Cambodia</description></item><item><title>Brazil interested in Russian diesel, gasoline supplies — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063905</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063905</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:01:16 +0000</pubDate><description>Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos emphasized that "diesel is especially important because Brazil's transportation system relies heavily on road freight"</description></item><item><title>Russia, Brazil plan to increase trade in national currencies — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063907</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063907</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:02:20 +0000</pubDate><description>The large trade deficit between the two countries limits the use of national currencies for trade and commercial transactions, the diplomat noted</description></item><item><title>Moscow blast kills 2 police near site of Russian general’s car bombing</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337600/moscow-blast-kills-2-police-near-site-russian-generals-car-bombing?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337600/moscow-blast-kills-2-police-near-site-russian-generals-car-bombing?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 07:11:31 +0000</pubDate><description>Three people were killed by a bomb on Wednesday in Moscow after two police officers approached a ⁠man acting suspiciously near the site where a senior general was killed two days ago by a car bomb that Russia said was planted by Ukrainian intelligence.
A string of Russian military figures and high-profile supporters of the war in ‍Ukraine have been assassinated during the nearly four-year-old conflict. Ukrainian military intelligence has said ‍it was responsible for a number of the...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/aab0f030-b95f-4a6a-bfca-e744eb7f3178_87c92397.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Does the US want to conquer Greenland? Trump’s new envoy weighs in</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337583/does-us-want-conquer-greenland-trumps-new-envoy-weighs?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337583/does-us-want-conquer-greenland-trumps-new-envoy-weighs?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:13:06 +0000</pubDate><description>US President Donald Trump’s newly appointed envoy to Greenland said on Tuesday that the Republican administration is looking to begin a conversation with residents of the semi-autonomous Danish territory about the best way forward for the strategically important island.
In his first extended comments since being appointed to the role this week, Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry said the Trump administration isn’t going to “go in there trying to conquer anybody” or try to “to take over anybody’s...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/5d0750ed-6894-45f0-b84e-a35853116fba_73bf0b89.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US hits 5 Europeans with visa bans in ‘censorship’ row</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337562/us-hits-5-europeans-visa-bans-censorship-row?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337562/us-hits-5-europeans-visa-bans-censorship-row?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate><description>The US State Department announced on Tuesday it was barring five Europeans it accused of leading efforts to pressure US tech firms to censor or suppress American viewpoints.
The Europeans, characterised by US Secretary of State Marco Rubio as “radical” activists and “weaponised” non-governmental organisations, fell afoul of a new visa policy announced in May to restrict the entry of foreigners deemed responsible for censorship of protected speech in the United States.
“For far too long,...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/ace82f0c-6782-4e2f-808d-5f72dcf4d36a_b8f5b932.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Russell Brand charged with new counts of rape, sexual assault in UK</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337564/russell-brand-charged-new-counts-rape-sexual-assault-uk?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337564/russell-brand-charged-new-counts-rape-sexual-assault-uk?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:51:34 +0000</pubDate><description>UK police said two new charges, of rape and sexual assault, had been issued on Tuesday against British comedian and actor Russell Brand.
The media personality turned anti-establishment influencer already pleaded not guilty in May to five charges - one count of rape, one of oral rape, two of sexual assault and one of indecent assault between 1999 and 2005.
“These new charges are in relation to two further women and are in addition to the charges issued to Brand in April 2025 which involved four...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/1cf6e8ef-e0ab-445f-8f25-9e6cded6a0ef_e3fbf766.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>SANA reports on meeting between Syrian foreign, defense ministers and Putin in Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063851</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063851</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:59:16 +0000</pubDate><description>The Kremlin press service has not yet reported such contact</description></item><item><title>Brazil concerned about Trump's actions towards Venezuela — ambassador to Russia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063855</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063855</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:22:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos also expressed hope that a military conflict between the United States and Venezuela will not occur</description></item><item><title>Sanctions against Russia have not hindered growth of its trade with Brazil — ambassador</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063857</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063857</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Today, Russia ranks eighth among Brazil's trading partners, Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos said</description></item><item><title>Brazil fully supports peace talks on Ukraine — ambassador to Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063863</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063863</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:04:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos stressed that Brazil has never supported the diplomatic isolation of Russia</description></item><item><title>None of BRICS members wants to leave association — Brazilian ambassador to Russia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063849</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063849</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:42:34 +0000</pubDate><description>Sergio Rodrigues dos Santos noted that BRICS is a constructive force in strengthening a multipolar world order that is becoming increasingly inclusive and democratic</description></item><item><title>US NATO envoy believes ball is in Russia's court in Ukrainian settlement</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063841</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063841</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:35:01 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Matthew Whitaker, Washington is trying to find out the maximum that Russia is willing to do to end the conflict</description></item><item><title>Parties to negotiations on Ukraine discussing four final documents — US NATO envoy</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063845</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063845</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:58:32 +0000</pubDate><description>There is a 20-point peace plan, together with sort of the multilateral security guarantees, the US specific security guarantees, and the post-peace economic growth and prosperity plan, Matthew Whitaker said</description></item><item><title>US Supreme Court blocks Trump’s National Guard deployment in Chicago</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337553/us-supreme-court-blocks-trumps-national-guard-deployment-chicago?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337553/us-supreme-court-blocks-trumps-national-guard-deployment-chicago?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:19:02 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Supreme Court refused on Tuesday to let Donald Trump send National Guard troops to the Chicago area ‌as the Republican president expands the use of the military for domestic purposes in a growing number of Democratic-led jurisdictions, a policy critics call an effort to punish adversaries and stifle dissent.
The justices let stand for ‍now a judge’s order blocking the deployment of hundreds of National Guard troops in a legal challenge brought by Illinois officials and local leaders. The...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/4ecdb8df-ff56-4a60-ae07-3432f1b6da10_8298f814.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>‘60 Minutes’ story on Trump immigration crackdown accidentally airs on Canadian app</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337552/60-minutes-story-trump-immigration-crackdown-accidentally-airs-canadian-app?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337552/60-minutes-story-trump-immigration-crackdown-accidentally-airs-canadian-app?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:53:04 +0000</pubDate><description>A news segment about the Trump administration’s immigration policy that was abruptly pulled from “60 Minutes” was mistakenly aired on a television app after the last-minute decision not to air it touched off a public debate about journalistic independence.
The segment featured interviews with migrants who were sent to a notorious El Salvador prison called the Terrorism Confinement Centre, or CECOT, under US President Donald Trump’s aggressive crackdown on immigration.
The story was pulled from...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/531db6a6-4af4-472d-a519-ae447536af64_be2de9b9.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Liquidation of Hezbollah’s military wing aligns with Lebanon’s security interests — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063831</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063831</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:06:01 +0000</pubDate><description>"In accordance with the government plan, the process of disarming Shiite fighters must extend to not only the south but all other regions of the country," Lebanese Foreign Minister Yousef Raji said</description></item><item><title>Putin warned Bush that NATO membership would split Ukraine — declassified documents</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063809</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063809</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:42:24 +0000</pubDate><description>During their meeting in Sochi in April 2008, Bush asked the Russian leader why Russia opposes to Ukraine’s NATO membership</description></item><item><title>US moves additional forces to Caribbean — media</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063817</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063817</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate><description>At least ten Osprey tiltrotor aircraft that are used in special operations, as well as a C-17 large military transport aircraft have been deployed to the area</description></item><item><title>Libya army chief and 4 others killed in Turkey plane crash</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337550/libya-army-chief-killed-turkey-plane-crash?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337550/libya-army-chief-killed-turkey-plane-crash?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:34:58 +0000</pubDate><description>A private jet carrying Libya’s military chief and four other people crashed after take-off from Turkey’s capital, Ankara, on Tuesday, killing everyone on board.
The Libyan military chief was in Ankara for high-level defence talks aimed at boosting military cooperation between the two countries and addressing regional issues, Turkish officials said.
Libyan Prime Minister Abdul-Hamid Dbeibah confirmed the death of General Muhammad Ali Ahmad al-Haddad and the others, saying in a statement on social...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/d22606b2-8ed2-4695-ac34-aa3afacfa127_1697354c.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Putin warned Bush that admitting Ukraine to NATO will lead to Russia-US confrontation</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063819</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063819</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:35:16 +0000</pubDate><description>The Russian leader stressed that this would create a threat of NATO moving its military bases and various arms systems to the exact proximity to the Russian border</description></item><item><title>West hindering peace deal in Ukraine — Georgian parliament speaker</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063807</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063807</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:14:17 +0000</pubDate><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin said at the defense ministry’s expanded board meeting on December 17 that European politicians are "whipping up hysteria" and "fearmongering" about an alleged clash with Russia</description></item><item><title>Armenia’s Mer Dzevov movement to announce its PM candidate in January</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063791</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063791</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:57:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Narek Karapetyan, coordinator of the movement, said the announcement will come on the day the political party is officially recognized</description></item><item><title>CSTO refutes information about Tajikistan’s appeal for assistance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063793</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063793</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:07:54 +0000</pubDate><description>The organization noted that Tajikistan’s interaction with its CSTO allies in the context of strengthening the border with Afghanistan is based on the relevant targeted interstate program approved at the 2024 session of the CSTO Collective Security Council in Astana</description></item><item><title>Presidents of Uzbekistan, US discuss prospects for bilateral cooperation</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063789</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063789</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:51:25 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Uzbek president’s press office, the leaders noted the increased intensity of bilateral political contacts, the creation of the US-Uzbekistan Business and Investment Council, practical work on the establishment of a joint investment fund</description></item><item><title>At least 120,000 people in Somalia displaced in September-December amid drought</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063775</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063775</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:25:59 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the local authorities, more than 4.6 million people in Somalia have been affected to by the drought</description></item><item><title>Hungary prepared to host Russia-US summit once countries ready — MP’s office</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063777</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063777</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:28:05 +0000</pubDate><description>Gergely Gulyas said there is neither a consensus nor conditions that would satisfy both Russia and Ukraine and allow them to sign a peace treaty</description></item><item><title>EU hindering, not helping Ukraine peace — Hungarian PM’s office</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063779</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063779</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Gergely Gulyas reported that Prime Minister Viktor Orban had briefed his cabinet members in detail on the results of the Brussels meeting</description></item><item><title>Deployment of Oreshnik in Belarus will not affect balance in Europe — defense minister</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063739</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063739</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Khrenin emphasized that the deployment is a direct response to aggressive actions by Western nations</description></item><item><title>Kazakh president invites Trump to visit Astana</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063751</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063751</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:13:13 +0000</pubDate><description>The two leaders exchanged views on the bilateral agenda and the current international situation, including Ukraine-related problems</description></item><item><title>Iraq says Iran stops gas supplies due to 'extraordinary circumstances'</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063761</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063761</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:35:03 +0000</pubDate><description>Ahmed Musa, head of the Iraqi ministry's press service, noted that Baghdad "has taken emergency measures to prevent a crisis at power plants until gas supplies resume"</description></item><item><title>Trump flew on Epstein jet ‘many more times than reported’, newly released file shows</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337549/trump-flew-epstein-jet-many-more-times-reported-newly-released-file-shows?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337549/trump-flew-epstein-jet-many-more-times-reported-newly-released-file-shows?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:11:04 +0000</pubDate><description>US President Donald Trump flew on convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein’s private jet “many more times than previously has been reported”, according to an email from a ‍New York prosecutor that forms part of a new batch of documents about Epstein that were released on Tuesday by the US Justice Department.
In an email dated January 7, 2020, the unidentified prosecutor wrote that flight records showed Trump had flown on Epstein’s private jet eight times during the 1990s.
Among those were at least...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/24/614e98c8-c68f-4d2e-adcb-9b2493c171df_24cac808.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Kazakhstan ready to offer negotiation platform for talks on Ukraine — president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063735</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063735</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate><description>Kazakhstan calls on all involved parties to show patience, flexibility, professionalism and nevertheless continue to search for a peace formula</description></item><item><title>2 men found guilty of UK plot to kill hundreds in  Jewish community</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337544/2-men-found-guilty-uk-plot-kill-hundreds-jewish-community?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337544/2-men-found-guilty-uk-plot-kill-hundreds-jewish-community?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:05:12 +0000</pubDate><description>Two men were found guilty on Tuesday of plotting to kill hundreds in an Islamic State-inspired gun rampage against the Jewish community in England, a planned attack investigators say shows the resurgent risk posed by the militant group.
Police and prosecutors said Walid Saadaoui, 38, and Amar Hussein, 52, who went on trial a week after an unrelated deadly attack on a synagogue in the nearby northwest city of Manchester in October, were Islamic extremists who wanted to use automatic firearms to...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/74c58672-18e6-4117-8ac4-c0b3ef4164ad_e90a37ab.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Serbian president says gas deal with Russia extended until end of March</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063723</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063723</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:16:21 +0000</pubDate><description>Aleksandar Vucic said that Serbia will have both electricity and enough gas for the upcoming winter season</description></item><item><title>Spain extends army participation in foreign missions for year</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063725</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063725</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:17:37 +0000</pubDate><description>Spain is present in 15 countries with about 4,000 deployed military personnel, whose capabilities, interoperability and experience have provided it with a first-class international reputation</description></item><item><title>South Korea's parliament supports creation of rebellion tribunal</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063727</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063727</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:23:19 +0000</pubDate><description>The leading opposition party, the Civil Force, from which former President Yoon Suk Yeol ran in 2022, opposed the tribunal and boycotted the vote</description></item><item><title>US Justice Department releases 30,000 Epstein files</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063699</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063699</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:47:33 +0000</pubDate><description>The department also noted that the files were redacted to protect the identities of possible victims</description></item><item><title>Polish parliament speaker anticipates growth in anti-Ukrainian moods</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063651</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063651</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:32:50 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Polish interior ministry, more than 1.5 Ukrainian citizens are currently living in the country</description></item><item><title>Colombian drug cartel members fighting for Ukraine in Kharkov Region — official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063653</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063653</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:42:13 +0000</pubDate><description>The Colombians are members of the Ares Group foreign private military corporation, which is fighting as part of the Ukrainian army</description></item><item><title>Gagauzia facing unprecedented pressure from Chisinau — party</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063659</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063659</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:56:52 +0000</pubDate><description>The Socialists believe that Chisinau’s desire to influence the autonomy’s ties with Turkey and Russia is behind this move</description></item><item><title>US nuclear umbrella absolute guarantee for NATO allies — Rutte</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063657</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063657</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate><description>NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte was responding to a question about whether European NATO allies need to bolster their nuclear deterrence capabilities</description></item><item><title>Majority of Ukrainians worry online voting could be used to fix presidential election</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063661</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063661</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, 36% of respondents believe that allowing online voting in elections will enable Ukrainians abroad to fully participate in the electoral process</description></item><item><title>Hungary refuses to ignore 'constitutional coup' in EU — minister for EU affairs</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063665</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063665</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:04:11 +0000</pubDate><description>Janos Boka warned that the Hungarian government "will not sit idly by" as this happens</description></item><item><title>Serbia supports Trump’s peace plan for Ukraine, offers venue for talks — top diplomat</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063669</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063669</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:14:51 +0000</pubDate><description>Marko Duric said that Belgrade strongly support US President Donald Trump’s peace plan and all other initiatives that may put an end to hostilities</description></item><item><title>Swedish activist Greta Thunberg arrested at UK pro-Palestinian protest</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337538/swedish-activist-greta-thunberg-arrested-uk-pro-palestinian-protest?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337538/swedish-activist-greta-thunberg-arrested-uk-pro-palestinian-protest?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:52:32 +0000</pubDate><description>London police on Tuesday arrested Swedish activist Greta Thunberg at a demonstration in support of pro-Palestinian hunger strikers, Palestinian activist groups said.
Thunberg’s arrest makes her the highest-profile person to be detained by police since the government banned the Palestine Action group under anti-terror laws.
“Greta Thunberg was arrested under the Terrorism Act at the Prisoners for Palestine lock-on protest,” Prisoners for Palestine said in a statement.
Thunberg was holding a sign...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/5f1417f2-a545-44c8-a09b-8cae4dd81e57_1a42d01d.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Syrian foreign, defense ministers to visit Moscow for talks — SANA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063613</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063613</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate><description>The Syrian delegation will also include representatives of the General Directorate of Intelligence</description></item><item><title>China, Russia boast vast potential of cooperation in international law sphere — expert</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063617</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063617</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:16:27 +0000</pubDate><description>Shu Hongshui said that Beijing consistently follows the multilateral approach and stands for supremacy of law in the global management system</description></item><item><title>Ukraine’s nuclear plants reduce power generation — news agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063625</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063625</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:27:35 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Acting Energy Minister Artyom Nekrasov, power outages are observed in certain regions of the country</description></item><item><title>US releases thousands of new Epstein-linked documents</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337534/us-releases-thousands-new-epstein-linked-documents?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337534/us-releases-thousands-new-epstein-linked-documents?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:39:11 +0000</pubDate><description>Thousands of new documents linked to the case of convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein were made available Tuesday by the US Department of Justice (DOJ), amid mounting criticism over the pace of the publication and heavy redactions.
At least 8,000 files were posted online, including hundreds of videos or audio recordings, notably surveillance footage from August 2019, the month Epstein was found dead in his jail cell while awaiting trial on sex trafficking charges.
The DOJ posted around 11,000...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/80e2cce6-fafb-4573-89c2-e0fa4431446f_2d936ef1.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>National security secretary Umerov returns to Ukraine after long absence</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063635</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063635</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:40:09 +0000</pubDate><description>He reported to Vladimir Zelensky about negotiations in the United States</description></item><item><title>German top diplomat says Russia’s military successes pose 'serious threat' to NATO</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063591</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063591</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:32:40 +0000</pubDate><description>Johann Wadephul also noted that there was no point in providing Ukraine with security guarantees without clear commitments from the United States</description></item><item><title>Fugitive Ukrainian businessman Mindich unlikely to return home — daily</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063593</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063593</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:35:45 +0000</pubDate><description>The daily reported earlier that its journalists located the fugitive Ukrainian businessman in Israel and published a photo of him there</description></item><item><title>New German intelligence chief holds phone call with Russian counterpart — portal</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063599</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063599</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:45:59 +0000</pubDate><description>The WDR broadcasting company’s investigative unit described the conversation as "a rare instance of direct contact between German and Russian agencies"</description></item><item><title>Turkey plans to expand its maritime monitoring system in Black Sea</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063583</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063583</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Ankara also intends to install this control system in the Eastern Mediterranean to better "monitor the situation in the area from Mersin to Cyprus"</description></item><item><title>Russia ‘strikes Ukraine before Christmas’ with over 650 drones, dozens of missiles</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337511/russia-strikes-ukraine-christmas-over-650-drones-dozens-missiles?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337511/russia-strikes-ukraine-christmas-over-650-drones-dozens-missiles?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:16:35 +0000</pubDate><description>Russia fired more than 650 drones and three dozen missiles at Ukraine in a large-scale attack that began during the night and stretched into daylight hours Tuesday, officials said. At least three people were killed, including a 4-year-old child.
The barrage struck homes and the power grid in 13 regions of Ukraine, causing widespread outages in bitter temperatures, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said, a day after he described recent progress on finding a peace deal “quite solid”.
The...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/f675cde5-47c1-47b4-b1e3-6262b4e4dc29_8729c327.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Traces of US involvement in cyberattack on Venezuela’s oil, gas company — Politico</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063475</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063475</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:43:07 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the report, it looks like a preconceived attack</description></item><item><title>Trump warns Colombian president to shut down cocaine labs</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063479</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063479</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:52:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Gustavo Petro needs to be careful because he has drug labs, they’re making cocaine in Colombia, the US president said</description></item><item><title>US uses China as pretext to justify nuclear forces upgrade — Chinese Foreign Ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063481</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063481</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:54:45 +0000</pubDate><description>Lin Jian also reaffirmed China’s stance, emphasizing that the country "strictly adheres to a no-first-use policy, maintains a nuclear strategy rooted in self-defense, and keeps its nuclear capabilities at the minimum level necessary to ensure national security"</description></item><item><title>Equatorial Guinea expresses readiness to host Russia-Africa summit</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063495</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063495</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:07:38 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Central African nation’s Ambassador to Moscow Luciano Nkogo Ndong Ayekaba, the country has "two congress centers, 54 mansions of 1,000 square meters, and numerous hotels"</description></item><item><title>Trump calls The New York Times ‘threat to national security’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063497</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063497</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:08:27 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the US leader, it is necessary to put an end to "fake articles and opinions"</description></item><item><title>At least 5 killed in US after Mexican plane on medical mission crashes in Texas fog</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337494/least-5-killed-us-after-mexican-plane-medical-mission-crashes-texas-fog?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337494/least-5-killed-us-after-mexican-plane-medical-mission-crashes-texas-fog?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:25:29 +0000</pubDate><description>A small Mexican Navy plane transporting a young medical patient and seven others crashed on Monday near Galveston, killing at least five people and setting off a search in waters along the Texas coast, officials said.
Four of the people on board were Navy officers and four were civilians, including a child, Mexico’s Navy said in a statement. Two of the passengers were from a non-profit that provides aid to Mexican children with severe burns, including transports to a Galveston hospital.
US...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/e5c280fe-9cdf-4a15-bc19-5db556ab34a0_77b75b4b.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Cambodia, Thailand set to end fire, build dialogue — Chinese MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063515</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063515</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:29:20 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the statement, Deng Xijun held mediation talks with authorities in both countries</description></item><item><title>Construction of ships for Trump's Golden Fleet expected to begin in 2030s — agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063463</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063463</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:39:45 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the US president, the first ship is going to be named the USS Defiant</description></item><item><title>Cambodian death toll from conflict with Thailand climbs to 21 — officials</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063465</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063465</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:46:56 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the report, 83 civilians were injured</description></item><item><title>US State Department refutes rift between Rubio, Witkoff</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063467</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063467</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:49:05 +0000</pubDate><description>White House Deputy Press Secretary Anna Kelly also pointed out that the information spread by NBC News is baseless, since both Rubio and Witkoff work together to settle the conflict in Ukraine</description></item><item><title>Fitch upgrades Ukraine’s rating to ‘CCC’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063439</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063439</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:58:53 +0000</pubDate><description>One of the factors behind the positive rating action was an agreement between Ukraine and the European Union on an interest-free loan amounting to 90 bln euro</description></item><item><title>Ukraine conflict likely to end in 2026 on terms unfavorable to Kiev — Politico</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063437</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063437</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:02:46 +0000</pubDate><description>Foreign affairs columnist Jamie Dettmer doubts a €90 billion loan will be sufficient to keep Ukraine solvent</description></item><item><title>US nuclear-powered submarine enters South Korean port</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063429</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063429</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:55:53 +0000</pubDate><description>This is the first visit by a nuclear-powered submarine under President Lee Jae-myung</description></item><item><title>Trump says talks with Russia and Ukraine to resolve conflict are going along okay</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063399</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063399</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:02:02 +0000</pubDate><description>"Everyone's tired of that war," the president added</description></item><item><title>Trump approves a plan to build two new Battleships for the US Navy</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063397</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063397</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:03:56 +0000</pubDate><description>The president specified that the United States could build 20-25 such ships</description></item><item><title>Trump says US needs Greenland for national security, not for minerals</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063403</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063403</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:33:32 +0000</pubDate><description>"We have more oil than any other country in the world," the president added</description></item><item><title>Mexican Navy plane crashes while landing in Texas</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063405</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063405</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:10:04 +0000</pubDate><description>There were eight people on board</description></item><item><title>Two people died as a Mexican Navy plane crashes while landing in Texas</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063407</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063407</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:11:50 +0000</pubDate><description>Four people survived the crash</description></item><item><title>IAEA Chief says he may visit Russia in March 2026</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063415</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063415</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:14:11 +0000</pubDate><description>Rafael Grossi said that he was working on organizing a visit to the Bushehr Nuclear Power Plant in Iran in the coming months</description></item><item><title>Death toll in Mexican Navy plane crash in Texas rises to five</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063419</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063419</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:18:13 +0000</pubDate><description>One crew member has not yet been found</description></item><item><title>US military strikes vessel in eastern Pacific, killing one — Pentagon</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063427</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063427</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:24:21 +0000</pubDate><description>The attack was conducted by Joint Task Force Southern Spear at the direction of Secretary of War Pete Hegseth on December 22</description></item><item><title>No need for needles? US approves Wegovy pill for weight loss</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337435/no-need-needles-us-approves-wegovy-pill-weight-loss?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337435/no-need-needles-us-approves-wegovy-pill-weight-loss?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:55:15 +0000</pubDate><description>US regulators on Monday gave the green light to a pill version of the blockbuster weight-loss drug Wegovy, the first daily oral medication to treat obesity.
The US Food and Drug Administration’s approval handed drug maker Novo Nordisk an edge over rival Eli Lilly in the race to market an obesity pill. Lilly’s oral drug, orforglipron, was still under review.
Both pills are GLP-1 drugs that work like widely used injectables to mimic a natural hormone that controls appetite and feelings of...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/b33eb2c1-9949-4ee8-b97c-94f280843c4e_46a094c7.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Trump unveils ‘Trump-class battleship’ in US shipbuilding push</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337404/trump-unveils-trump-class-battleship-us-shipbuilding-push?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337404/trump-unveils-trump-class-battleship-us-shipbuilding-push?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:21:46 +0000</pubDate><description>US President Donald Trump announced the US Navy will build a new “Trump-class” battleship as part of the White House push to modernise a fleet that has been hobbled by years of cost overruns and delays.
A poster displayed at the event at Trump’s gilded Mar-a-Lago estate featured an artist’s rendering of a sleek-looking warship dubbed the USS Defiant, cutting through choppy waters with a laser beam shooting from its deck and smoke billowing from a target in the background.
Next to the ship was a...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/a967d46d-c6ed-4723-aa6d-8549830f0785_fdb8499e.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>PM Mark Carney names financier Mark Wiseman as Canada’s ambassador to the US</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337403/pm-mark-carney-names-financier-mark-wiseman-canadas-ambassador-us?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337403/pm-mark-carney-names-financier-mark-wiseman-canadas-ambassador-us?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:46:43 +0000</pubDate><description>Prime Minister Mark Carney announced on Monday that financier Mark Wiseman will serve as Canada’s next ambassador to the United States, an appointment that comes at a critical time in relations between the two major trading partners.
Wiseman will assume the role on February 15 and will be involved in negotiations with the United States regarding the review of their free trade agreement.
“Mark Wiseman brings immense experience, contacts, and deep commitment at this crucial time of transformation...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/f340febf-eb36-491a-8416-bdbb2d5d49b5_c8c1adcb.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Corruption charges spark violent protests against Albanian government</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337402/corruption-charges-spark-violent-protests-against-albanian-government?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337402/corruption-charges-spark-violent-protests-against-albanian-government?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:38:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Protesters in Tirana, Albania hurled petrol bombs at the government building housing ‌Prime Minister Edi Rama’s office on Monday, demanding ‍the government’s resignation after prosecutors indicted the deputy prime minister for alleged corruption.
Political tensions in Albania have escalated in recent weeks after the ⁠accusations were made against Deputy Prime Minister Belinda Balluku.
Along with several officials and private companies, she has been accused of using state funds to favour some...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/0bfa55da-34a5-45eb-9271-06c3d5dbd3cd_3b032b03.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Call of Duty co-creator Vince Zampella killed in car crash</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337401/call-duty-co-creator-vince-zampella-killed-car-crash?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337401/call-duty-co-creator-vince-zampella-killed-car-crash?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:28:15 +0000</pubDate><description>Vince Zampella, the acclaimed co-creator of the video gaming juggernaut Call of Duty, has died in a car crash, US media reported on Monday.
According to local broadcaster NBC4, the 55-year-old developer and executive died on Sunday while driving his Ferrari on a scenic road north of Los Angeles. His studios created some of the world’s bestselling video games.
Zampella was best known for co-creating the Call of Duty franchise and founding Respawn Entertainment, the studio behind Titanfall, Apex...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/1164ec77-a99d-4d16-bd20-6c0d9248a8fd_55f131f0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Moscow, Caracas reiterate brotherly ties, strategic cooperation — top Venezuelan diplomat</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063379</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063379</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>"During the phone call with Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, we again reiterated our brotherly relations, mutual respect, and strategic partnership between us," Yvan Gil Pinto said</description></item><item><title>Netanyahu to discuss Iran’s nuclear activities, next phase of Gaza plan with Trump</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337396/netanyahu-discuss-irans-nuclear-activities-next-phase-gaza-plan-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337396/netanyahu-discuss-irans-nuclear-activities-next-phase-gaza-plan-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:33:22 +0000</pubDate><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on ‍Monday he will discuss Iran’s nuclear activities during his visit next week with US President Donald Trump.
Speaking at a joint press conference with Greek Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis and Cypriot President Nikos Christodoulides in Jerusalem, Netanyahu said Israel was aware Iran had been conducting “exercises” recently, without elaborating.
Earlier on Monday, Iranian state media reported Iran had held missile drills in various cities...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/eb3b8546-b8c7-4182-b91e-2a53d60147fe_638ed991.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Poland to build training range for joint maneuvers with Lithuania in Suwalki Gap</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063369</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063369</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:34:40 +0000</pubDate><description>"There are no other examples of such facilities in Europe," Lithuanian Vice-minister of National Defense Bronius Bieliauskas said</description></item><item><title>Venezuela reiterates its commitment to peace, but will defend its sovereignty — Maduro</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063371</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063371</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:40:11 +0000</pubDate><description>The president recalled that the US military had staged 28 attacks on civilian ships in the Caribbean and the eastern Pacific, "executing 104 people extrajudicially" and stressed that Venezuela had done nothing that could justify the United States’ military pressure</description></item><item><title>Christmas in Europe to be peaceful, but military threat remains — Hungarian leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063377</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063377</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:43:01 +0000</pubDate><description>Preparations for a war with Russia "are still under way in Europe behind closed doors," Viktor Orban said</description></item><item><title>London recklessly provokes US into confrontation with Russia — UK journalist</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063219</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063219</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate><description>Frank Wright said "it's not realistic for the Europeans or the British to win a war against Russia"</description></item><item><title>Top Turkish diplomat says phase two of Gaza deal may begin in early 2026</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063365</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063365</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:36:46 +0000</pubDate><description>The transfer of power to the Palestinians is at the top of the agenda now, noted Hakan Fidan</description></item><item><title>UK man, 5 others charged with more than 60 sex offences against woman</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337394/uk-man-5-others-charged-more-60-sex-offences-against-woman?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337394/uk-man-5-others-charged-more-60-sex-offences-against-woman?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:02:22 +0000</pubDate><description>A British man was charged on Monday with drugging and raping his ex-wife, and five other men were charged with sexual offences against her over a 13-year period, UK police said.
Philip Young, 49, will appear on Tuesday at a court in Swindon, west of London, charged with dozens of offences against his 48-year-old former spouse Joanne Young, who has waived her legal right to anonymity.
The alleged offences include multiple counts of rape and administering a substance with intent to stupefy or...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/5d65f0d1-31d3-41a3-858a-1d9ee95c2473_839829be.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Two civilians die after Kurds shell Aleppo — TV</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063349</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063349</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:50:17 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the repot, the shelling attack targeted Aleppo’s northern Al-Jamiliya neighborhood</description></item><item><title>CIS leaders note importance of strengthening cultural dialogue — Uzbekistan's leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063335</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063335</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:06:47 +0000</pubDate><description>The heads of the CIS states earlier visited the exposition of artistic silver, as well as the Alexander, Picket and Coat of Arms Halls</description></item><item><title>Trump administration to recall 48 heads of diplomatic missions — NYP</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063337</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063337</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:08:11 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, the Trump administration has not yet appointed the heads of diplomatic missions in its key partner countries</description></item><item><title>Top Democrat urges Senate to sue over Justice Department’s staggered Epstein files release</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337393/top-democrat-urges-senate-sue-over-justice-departments-staggered-epstein-files-release?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337393/top-democrat-urges-senate-sue-over-justice-departments-staggered-epstein-files-release?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:08:42 +0000</pubDate><description>Chuck Schumer, the Senate’s top Democrat, urged his colleagues on Monday to take legal action over the Justice Department’s incremental and heavily redacted release of records pertaining to the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.
Schumer introduced a resolution that, if passed, would direct the Senate to file or join lawsuits aimed at forcing the Justice Department to comply with the Epstein Files Transparency Act, the law enacted last month that required disclosure of records by last...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/924df5a6-c36e-46bb-9dfa-b790c1a927f4_67f340b2.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Europe lacks money to sponsor Kiev, needs to look for compromise — French MP</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063339</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063339</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:09:01 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Thierry Mariani, today, little depends on Europe as far as the Ukrainian settlement is concerned</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian parliament speaker moves to begin legislative process on holding elections</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063345</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063345</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Ruslan Stefanchuk, the biggest thing will be to create conditions for the military to vote at the front and their right to be elected</description></item><item><title>Ex-Israeli PM accuses Netanyahu of ‘treason’ over alleged Qatar funding to aides</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337391/ex-israeli-pm-accuses-netanyahu-treason-over-alleged-qatar-funding-aides?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337391/ex-israeli-pm-accuses-netanyahu-treason-over-alleged-qatar-funding-aides?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:01:44 +0000</pubDate><description>Former Israeli premier Naftali Bennett, widely regarded as a leading contender in next year’s legislative elections, called on Monday for the resignation of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, accusing his office of “treason” over alleged Qatari funding to his aides.
Netanyahu has also announced he intends to seek another term in office ahead of the legislative elections scheduled for October 2026.
At the centre of the controversy is the “Qatargate” affair, in which close associates of Netanyahu...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/7ff4f6b0-6a50-4eea-b231-ca53944992ac_90445bdd.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Tanker seized by US near Venezuela towed to Texas port — TV</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063323</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063323</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:15:21 +0000</pubDate><description>The report says the vessel has been anchored approximately 50 miles from the port city of Galveston</description></item><item><title>Democrats to move to impeach Trump if they win Congress in 2026</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063327</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063327</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate><description>Speaker of the House of Representatives, member of the Republican Party Mike Johnson pointed out that the Democratic Party intends to "dismantle" the foundations of the country</description></item><item><title>UK street artist Banksy unveils latest mural in central London</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337392/uk-street-artist-banksy-unveils-latest-mural-central-london?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337392/uk-street-artist-banksy-unveils-latest-mural-central-london?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:29:02 +0000</pubDate><description>British street artist Banksy unveiled his latest work in central London on Monday amid speculation over an identical second work which has appeared elsewhere in the city.
The black and white mural painted on the side of an old building in Bayswater shows two people, probably children, in winter hats and Wellington boots lying down, looking up and pointing to the sky.
Banksy, whose real identity has not been revealed, posted an image of the work on his official Instagram account on Monday.
A...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/da982691-9426-461e-91c1-313a302ad7e8_87570607.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Pashinyan sees nuances in Trump route implementation tied to Russia relations</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063301</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063301</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:43 +0000</pubDate><description>The Armenian Prime Minister said that Yerevan is engaged in constructive bilateral negotiations with the United States</description></item><item><title>Pashinyan thanks Putin for facilitating peace process with Azerbaijan</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063303</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063303</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate><description>The Armenian Prime Minister expressed confidence that peace between Armenia and Azerbaijan has already been achieved, as trains from Russia now travel to Armenia through Azerbaijani territory</description></item><item><title>‘Driving Home For Christmas’ singer Chris Rea dies at 74</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337389/driving-home-christmas-singer-chris-rea-dies-74?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337389/driving-home-christmas-singer-chris-rea-dies-74?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:31:49 +0000</pubDate><description>British singer Chris Rea, whose songs include the festive hit “Driving Home For Christmas”, has died at the age of 74, a spokesperson for his family said on Monday.
The Middlesbrough-born musician was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer and had his pancreas removed in 2001, and in 2016 he suffered a stroke.
Rea found fame in the late 1970s and 1980s with hits such as “Fool (If You Think It’s Over)”, “Let’s Dance” and “The Road to Hell”.
A statement from his family to the Press Association said:...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/23/7d6b639f-ef50-4754-8976-00057f4318f4_fa17e534.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Europe stagnates culturally and economically — Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063313</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063313</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President added that Europe's immigration policies have caused a significant backlash from the native population</description></item><item><title>Paramount vs Netflix: Ellison guarantees US$40 billion for son’s Warner Bros bid</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337388/paramount-vs-netflix-ellison-guarantees-us40-billion-sons-warner-bros-bid?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337388/paramount-vs-netflix-ellison-guarantees-us40-billion-sons-warner-bros-bid?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>Oracle tech tycoon Larry Ellison is offering a US$40.4 billion personal guarantee to back Paramount’s hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery, deepening a bidding war with Netflix, a statement said on Monday.
The amended proposal, worth a total US$108 billion from the company run by Ellison’s son David, addresses concerns raised by Warner Bros’ board, which saw the Paramount bid as too risky and asked shareholders to accept a competing buyout offer from Netflix.
Netflix shocked the industry on...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/c1c045bf-b3ec-4647-8f72-a9a5b4be2fed_44f09af1.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Two US mercenaries eliminated in Ukraine — Newsweek</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063289</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063289</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:45:43 +0000</pubDate><description>According to reports from the accounts of the families of the deceased, Jones and Zacherl were serving with international forces under the command of Ukraine's GUR military intelligence agency</description></item><item><title>Slovakia refuses to vote nay on EU's Ukraine financing plan — PM</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063273</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063273</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:12:40 +0000</pubDate><description>Robert Fico and other members of the Slovak government have repeatedly stated that the country insists on an immediate ceasefire and peace negotiations while refusing to finance the continuation of the conflict</description></item><item><title>Nigeria says ‘spat’ with Trump over killing of Christians ‘largely resolved’</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337384/nigeria-says-spat-trump-over-killing-christians-largely-resolved?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337384/nigeria-says-spat-trump-over-killing-christians-largely-resolved?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:45:55 +0000</pubDate><description>The Nigerian government on Monday said its recent diplomatic dust-up with the United States, in which President Donald Trump threatened military intervention over the alleged killing of Christians, “has been largely resolved”.
Trump unexpectedly tore into the west African nation in October and November, saying that Christians there faced an “existential threat” that amounted to “genocide” amid Nigeria’s myriad armed conflicts.
The diplomatic offensive was welcomed by some but interpreted by...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/155b6caa-6a7a-4f15-b145-3683cfa3907e_500ba570.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukraine deal close, but most difficult issues remain unresolved — Finnish leader</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063213</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063213</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:07:21 +0000</pubDate><description>According to media reports, Alexander Stubb has maintained close contact with US President Donald Trump</description></item><item><title>Certain countries, politicians oppose Trump's Ukraine peace plan — Georgian official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063229</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063229</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:10:45 +0000</pubDate><description>Kakha Kaladze declined to specify which countries and politicians are obstructing Trump's efforts to end the Ukraine war</description></item><item><title>Kiev acknowledges that it will probably lose Donetsk — JD Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063227</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063227</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:11:34 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President suggested that territorial concessions "could be 12 months from now, it could be longer than that," stating that "territorial concession is a significant hold-up in the negotiations"</description></item><item><title>Trump administration triples ‘self-deport’ stipend to US$3,000</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337382/trump-administration-triples-self-deport-stipend-us3000?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337382/trump-administration-triples-self-deport-stipend-us3000?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:14:46 +0000</pubDate><description>The Trump administration has tripled its stipend offer to migrants who choose to voluntarily “self-deport” ‌from the United States to US$3,000, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) ‍said on Monday.
The stipend would be given to people in the US illegally who sign up to leave the country by the end of the ⁠year, DHS said. The offer would include a free flight back to their home countries, it said.
“Illegal aliens should take advantage of this gift and self-deport because if they don’t, we...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/aee8995f-d299-48c6-995d-fa11d4775ee6_8a0760e7.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Uganda plans to gradually abolish visas for Russians — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063185</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063185</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate><description>At present, visas are processed online and issued within two days</description></item><item><title>No free elections in Ukraine until Russians returned their rights — opposition politician</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063173</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063173</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:49:39 +0000</pubDate><description>"Zelensky has every lever at his disposal to curb and distort the will of the people and impose his conditions on the country in his personal concentration camp," Viktor Medvedchuk said</description></item><item><title>Up to ten Oreshnik systems to be deployed in Belarus — president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063191</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063191</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:56:22 +0000</pubDate><description>Alexander Lukashenko said an Oreshnik system has entered combat duty in the republic and denied media reports that it was deployed in Slutsk</description></item><item><title>Vance rings alarm bell over growing 'Islamist' presence in European politics</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063059</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063059</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:04:34 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President also warned of potential long-term risks to Europe-Washington relations across various fields</description></item><item><title>Hungarian PM objects to sending tax dollars to Ukraine, advocates spending money at home</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063071</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063071</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:14:20 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban has repeatedly confirmed that his government calls for resolving the Ukraine conflict peacefully and has no plans to spend Hungarian taxpayer money on further military activities in the country</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian soldiers deserting due to being underpaid — outlet</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063137</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063137</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:14:51 +0000</pubDate><description>A serviceman suggested that AWOL could become an even more widespread phenomenon in the Ukrainian army in the coming months</description></item><item><title>Did CBS postpone a ‘60 Minutes’ report on El Salvador prison for ‘political’ reasons?</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337379/did-cbs-postpone-60-minutes-report-el-salvador-prison-political-reasons?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337379/did-cbs-postpone-60-minutes-report-el-salvador-prison-political-reasons?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:38:22 +0000</pubDate><description>CBS News pulled a 60 Minutes report on El Salvador’s CECOT prison just hours before its ‍scheduled Sunday broadcast, saying it would air at a future time.
“The broadcast line-up for tonight’s edition of 60 Minutes has been updated,” the programme posted on social media. “Our report ‘Inside CECOT’ will air in a future broadcast,” the programme posted on social media three hours before it was slated to air.
A CBS News spokesperson said in ⁠an email that the segment “needed additional reporting”....</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/593db9f2-4637-4df3-be5c-a00c5602cbf9_84afa89d.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Pentagon deems Lakenheath base in England unfit for nuclear weapons — media</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063007</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063007</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate><description>The authors of the document noted that one reason Lakenheath cannot host nuclear weapons is that "some of those involved in the US nuclear operation would not have quick access to a toilet during an Armageddon-style scenario"</description></item><item><title>US, Israel may face significant disagreements despite their alliance — JD Vance</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063009</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063009</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:01:40 +0000</pubDate><description>The US Vice President said that it is important for Washington to maintain room for maneuver in its relations with the Jewish state and to have the ability to distance itself from its foreign policy at certain stages</description></item><item><title>Japan’s nuclear ambitions undermine stability in Asia Pacific — Chinese MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063013</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063013</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:06:03 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Chinese Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Lin Jian, Beijing believes that it is unacceptable for Japan to undermine the international nuclear non-proliferation regime, citing fictitious threats</description></item><item><title>Vance indicates breakthrough in Ukraine talks between Russia, United States</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063019</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063019</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:10:04 +0000</pubDate><description>The US vice president said that America would continue to make diplomatic efforts towards a Ukraine resolution</description></item><item><title>Macron played key role in derailing EU plan on Russian assets at summit — Politico</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063023</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063023</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:19:35 +0000</pubDate><description>At the summit, the French leader held discussions with Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, the report stated</description></item><item><title>Ukraine talks progress, territorial issues: statements by US vice president</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063025</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063025</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:22:28 +0000</pubDate><description>JD Vance noted progress on the Ukraine front during the negotiations with Russian Presidential Special Envoy Kirill Dmitriev in Miami</description></item><item><title>Iran’s missile program will never be up for discussion or bargaining — Foreign Ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063031</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063031</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:30:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Iranian Foreign Ministry Spokesman Esmail Baghaei argued that Western demands for restrictions on Iran’s missile program are nothing but double standards</description></item><item><title>Europe pressures Kiev to stem departure of youth to other countries — newspaper</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063033</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063033</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate><description>El Pais also characterizes Ukraine’s demographic situation as catastrophic</description></item><item><title>Thailand, Cambodia to discuss ceasefire deal on Wednesday</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2063035</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2063035</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:33:12 +0000</pubDate><description>Thai Foreign Minister Sihasak Phuangketkeow said these talks will be conducted within the framework of the existing Joint Border Committee</description></item><item><title>Denmark angered over Trump naming envoy to Greenland, summons US ambassador</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337363/denmark-angered-over-trump-naming-envoy-greenland-summons-us-ambassador?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337363/denmark-angered-over-trump-naming-envoy-greenland-summons-us-ambassador?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:54:25 +0000</pubDate><description>The Danish foreign minister said on Monday he will summon the US ambassador, insisting that everyone – including the United States – must respect “the territorial integrity of the Kingdom of Denmark” after US President Donald Trump announced the appointment of Louisiana’s governor as the US ‌special envoy to Greenland.
During his presidential transition and early second term, Trump repeatedly pushed for US control over Greenland, a semi-autonomous Danish territory, and has not ruled out using...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/368ce758-de9e-49ca-bf1d-08fa974d3d42_c2bb63f9.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US State Department denies plans to allocate $60 billion for Gaza's reconstruction</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062957</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062957</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:06:26 +0000</pubDate><description>The State Department, nonetheless, does not deny the existence of a Gaza reconstruction plan</description></item><item><title>No peace deal reached between Cambodia, Thailand at meeting in Malaysia</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062979</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062979</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:12:24 +0000</pubDate><description>The negotiations reached a deadlock after the Thai side demanded that Cambodia fulfill three conditions to end hostilities</description></item><item><title>Iran continues to demand IAEA condemn Israeli strikes on nuclear facilities — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062975</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062975</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:12:53 +0000</pubDate><description>Esmail Baghaei pointed out that the agency’s failure to condemn the Israeli attacks not only indicates indifference to these illegal acts but also potentially signals to Israel that such aggression may be repeated</description></item><item><title>Iran promises not to break off relations with Russia at Europe’s request</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062983</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062983</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:14:42 +0000</pubDate><description>According to Esmaeil Baghaei, European countries should pay attention to their behavior and analyze why the conflict in Ukraine arose in the first place</description></item><item><title>Death toll in Indonesia floods exceeds 1,100 — agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062949</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062949</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:47:53 +0000</pubDate><description>About 7,000 people were injured</description></item><item><title>Uganda wants to cooperate with Russia in oil, gas sector — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062953</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062953</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:53:06 +0000</pubDate><description>The African country also intends to develop trade with Russia in many areas</description></item><item><title>US Department of Justice plans no redactions in Epstein files to project famous people</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062925</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062925</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:05:19 +0000</pubDate><description>The agency pointed out that some of the material was temporarily removed based on requests from victims and their lawyers</description></item><item><title>New French missile could form basis of European 'nuclear umbrella,' expert says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062921</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062921</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:08:56 +0000</pubDate><description>Alexander Stepanov pointed out that the ASMPA-R has successfully completed tests with the Rafale M carrier-based aircraft, confirming its operational compatibility</description></item><item><title>EU loan to Kiev funds continuation of conflict — political director for Hungarian PM</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062891</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062891</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:14:47 +0000</pubDate><description>Viktor Orban argued that the move would ultimately lead to cuts in other areas of European countries’ budgets, emphasizing that Hungary will not participate in the loan</description></item><item><title>European leaders tend to delay decision making, Romanian president says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062865</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062865</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:16:43 +0000</pubDate><description>Nicusor Dan stressed that EU politics was a democratic process, but "the debates are a little bit too long"</description></item><item><title>Another 25 children added to Ukraine’s database of unwanted persons</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062881</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062881</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:34:35 +0000</pubDate><description>All of them were born between 2015 and 2021</description></item><item><title>White House launches livestream highlighting Trump administration’s 2025 achievements</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062887</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062887</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:46:58 +0000</pubDate><description>The US leader appears as an animated character, seated in an armchair next to a Christmas tree, surrounded by gifts, and reading a book</description></item><item><title>Drones entering Romania’s airspace pose no threat, president says</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062883</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062883</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:47:20 +0000</pubDate><description>Nicusor Dan believes the drones that have been recorded in the country’s airspace have not intentionally been sent on its territory</description></item><item><title>Russian general killed in Moscow car bombing, investigators say</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337301/russian-general-killed-moscow-car-bombing-investigators-say?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337301/russian-general-killed-moscow-car-bombing-investigators-say?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:20:25 +0000</pubDate><description>A Russian general was killed on Monday morning after an explosive device detonated underneath his car in southern Moscow, investigators said.
Lieutenant General Fanil Sarvarov, head of the Operational Training Directorate of the Russian Armed Forces General Staff, died from his injuries, Svetlana Petrenko, official spokesperson for Russia’s Investigative Committee, said.
“Investigators are pursuing numerous lines of enquiry regarding the murder. One of these is that the crime was orchestrated by...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/fec8580a-7d9d-4d5c-9818-e19759e4e7d6_14a26ac0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukrainian authorities evacuate almost 147,000 civilians from frontline areas</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062839</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062839</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 06:08:01 +0000</pubDate><description>More than 16,500 of those evacuated are children</description></item><item><title>Critical infrastructure facility damaged in Ukrainian city of Odessa</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062835</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062835</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:24:52 +0000</pubDate><description>One of the city districts was partially left without electricity</description></item><item><title>Trump names Louisiana governor as US special envoy to Greenland</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062837</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062837</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:38:44 +0000</pubDate><description>The American leader has repeatedly said that Greenland should become a part of the United States</description></item><item><title>Conflict with Thailand leaves 525,000 Cambodians dispaced — ministry</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062833</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062833</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:00:10 +0000</pubDate><description>The number includes 274,800 women and 167,100 children</description></item><item><title>Scientist Hu Haitao leaves US for China, Mexico tariff shock: 5 weekend reads you missed</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:30:08 +0000</pubDate><description>We have put together stories from our coverage last weekend to help you stay informed about news across Asia and beyond. If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider subscribing.
1. Mexico’s 50% tariff shock shuts Asia’s North American trade bypass

2. China warns India: ‘don’t even think about stealing our 6th Dalai Lama’

3. Hong Kong district officer apologises over outfit choice at firefighter’s funeral

4. Thailand’s tourism crown slips as troubles in paradise mount

5....</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/c76f83e4-5116-402f-9126-a2d0b9c538c7_b474ee7b.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Republika Srpska’s new president maintains course of friendship with Russia — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062803</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062803</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:45:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Yury Pilipson recalled that "the early presidential elections in the Republika Srpska held on November 23 were the result of a campaign launched under pressure from Western countries to illegally remove Milorad Dodik, the leader of the Serbs in Bosnia and Herzegovina, from power"</description></item><item><title>No new Russia-US meeting on irritants planned yet — embassy in Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062805</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062805</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:19:57 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, US diplomats noted that Washington considers "the channel of bilateral operations as a constructive and permanent platform for negotiations to stabilize the work of the missions"</description></item><item><title>Brussels promised that sanctions would crush Russia, but they destroyed Europe — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062807</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062807</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:22:38 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that this is the price of poor decision-making and that negotiations are needed</description></item><item><title>European Commission becomes ‘Titanic’ dragging EU down with it — magazine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062817</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062817</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:34:06 +0000</pubDate><description>According to journalist Rafael Pinto Borges, Brussels has experienced institutional decline, which the European Commission prefers to ignore</description></item><item><title>Trump administration recalls heads of nearly 30 foreign diplomatic missions — news agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062819</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062819</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:03:54 +0000</pubDate><description>According to its information, the heads of US missions abroad have been notified that their terms in their current positions will expire in January</description></item><item><title>No Ukraine ceasefire breakthrough despite ‘productive and constructive’ talks</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:30:27 +0000</pubDate><description>US and Ukrainian envoys issued a joint statement on Sunday that hailed “productive and constructive” talks in Miami but did not announce any apparent breakthrough in efforts to end the war with Russia.
Top representatives from both Ukraine and Russia, as well as Kyiv’s European allies, have been in southern Florida over the past several days for a series of separate talks hosted by US President Donald Trump’s special envoy, Steve Witkoff.
The meetings were the latest in a weeks-long diplomatic...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/5cdf1648-0b89-46bb-b500-fb0b2c4cd139_b36102a0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US tanker with Venezuelan oil left for US — official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062821</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062821</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:51:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Vice President and Hydrocarbons Minister Delcy Rodriguez also posted a video of the tanker leaving port</description></item><item><title>Witkoff calls Russia-US consultations on Ukraine ‘productive, constructive’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062797</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062797</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:34:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Moscow highly values Washington's efforts to settle the conflict and strengthen global security, he added</description></item><item><title>US Air Force fighter jet intercepts aircraft for approaching Trump's residence</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062785</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062785</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate><description>F‑16 intercepted an aircraft that entered restricted airspace over Palm Beach, NORAD reported</description></item><item><title>Continuation of Ukraine conflict beneficial to politicians, arms dealers, bankers — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062787</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062787</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:14:57 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that Europeans deserve better, because Europe needs peace</description></item><item><title>US, Ukraine discuss sequence of next steps during consultations — Witkoff</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062769</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062769</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:44:21 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Special Representative of the US president, the parties, in particular, held "a separate constructive meeting"</description></item><item><title>Israeli foreign minister urges Jews to move to Israel a week after Sydney attack</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:11:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar called on Sunday for Jews in Western countries to move to Israel to escape rising antisemitism, one week after 15 were shot dead at a Jewish event in Sydney.
“Jews have the right to live in safety everywhere. But we see and fully understand what is happening, and we have a certain historical experience.
“Today, Jews are being hunted across the world,” Saar said at a public candle lighting marking the last day of the Jewish festival of Hanukkah.
“Today I call...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/e5780976-ffcf-4b84-b7f9-b4d3b9443b98_8ea3fbf3.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukrainian journalists say took pictures of Mindich in Israel</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062775</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062775</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:14:30 +0000</pubDate><description>The details are promised to be released later</description></item><item><title>Thousands cheer as the sun rises on winter solstice at Britain’s Stonehenge</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate><description>Thousands of people cheered and danced around Stonehenge as the sun rose over the prehistoric stone circle on Sunday, the winter solstice.
The crowds, many dressed as druids and pagans, had gathered before dawn, waiting patiently in the dark, cold field in Wiltshire, southwest England. Some sang and beat drums while others took time to reflect among the huge stone pillars.
Many make the pilgrimage to the stone circle every summer and winter and consider it a spiritual experience.
The ancient...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/945907eb-e8b8-4086-842e-b15d4daeaa9e_8c84218a.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Maduro condemns attacks on tankers carrying Venezuelan oil</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062763</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062763</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:05:51 +0000</pubDate><description>He noted that the Venezuelan people and all social strata of society remain steadfast in defending peace and national stability</description></item><item><title>US in pursuit of third tanker off coast of Venezuela — Bloomberg</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062755</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062755</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:51:49 +0000</pubDate><description>The reason is Donald Trump's tightening of the oil blockade against the government of Nicolas Maduro, noted Bloomberg</description></item><item><title>Nigerian government frees 130 kidnapped Catholic schoolchildren</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:53:26 +0000</pubDate><description>Nigerian authorities have secured the release of 130 kidnapped schoolchildren taken by gunmen from a Catholic school in November, a presidential spokesman said on Sunday, after 100 were freed earlier this month.
“Another 130 abducted Niger state pupils released, none left in captivity,” Sunday Dare said in a post on social media.
In late November, hundreds of pupils and staff were kidnapped from St Mary’s boarding school in north-central Niger state though the exact number and whether all are...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/97a37352-687c-42c1-ab81-c29a3500e5e8_a622b7ba.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>UK’s Starmer discusses Ukraine peace efforts in call with Trump</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:18:11 +0000</pubDate><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer discussed efforts to achieve a “just ‌and lasting end” to the war in Ukraine on Sunday with US President Donald Trump, Starmer’s Downing Street office said in a statement, after talks between officials in Florida.
“The two leaders began by reflecting ⁠on the war in Ukraine,” Starmer’s office said in a readout of the call, adding they had discussed the work of the so-called Coalition of the Willing countries that have pledged to support Ukraine.
“The Prime...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/7da60daf-1470-4b23-8368-3fe5bce75459_bd8a2294.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item>
      <title>Russia-Africa Forum agree plan of actions for 2026-2029 — top Egyptian diplomat</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062509</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062509</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to Badr Abdelatty, Russia and African countries agreed to "develop relations and hold political consultations on the basis of the norms of international law and the principle of non-interference into countries’ domestic affairs"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, Qatar, Egypt, Turkey report progress in implementing Gaza ceasefire phase one</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062515</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062515</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>As follows from the document, they held talks in Miami, Florida</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyz president arrives in Russia on working visit</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062519</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062519</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Sadyr Japarov has arrived to take part in the meeting of the Supreme Eurasian Economic Council and the informal meeting of CIS leaders in St. Petersburg, the press service of the Kyrgyz leader said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aggression against Venezuela may lead to humanitarian catastrophe — Brazilian leader</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062521</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062521</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva called on the countries of the region to consolidate their efforts to preserve it as a zone of peace and stability</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Egyptian diplomat describes Miami talks on Gaza as good</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062523</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062523</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Egyptian Foreign Minister Badr Abdelatty also expressed hope for the soonest beginning of the implementation of the Gaza deal second phase</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky admits that Kiev will not be able to finance 800,000-strong army</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062527</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062527</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Zelensky said that he maintains dialogue with Western leaders concerning partial financing of Ukrainian army at the expense of the partners</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US department confirms detention of tanker near Venezuelan coast</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062533</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062533</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"The United States will continue to pursue the illicit movement of sanctioned oil," the Head of the Department of Homeland Security Kristi Noem said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanker apprehended by the US near Venezuela sailed under flag of Panama — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062535</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062535</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the newspaper, the cargo belonged to an oil trader from China that supplies oil from Venezuela to Chinese refineries</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz finds himself in isolation in Europe due to position on Russian assets — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062545</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062545</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>German Chancellor attempted till the last "to praise advantages of the de facto expropriation of Russian assets, downplaying risks at the same time," the newspaper said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US National Intelligence confident Russia not planning to control entire Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062553</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062553</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard called such information about Russia's plans "a lie and propaganda"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump at ‘risk of becoming the deep state’ after Epstein file omissions</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Extensive redactions and the limited number of documents released related to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein angered some Republicans and did little to defuse a scandal threatening the party ahead of the 2026 midterm election.
The Trump administration touted this week’s release of a cache of Epstein-related files as a show of transparency, but a handful of Republican lawmakers and right-wing media figures joined Democrats in ‍blasting Friday’s disclosures as inadequate and possibly in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/ea215dd0-b670-4b62-93dc-10d73ab67e6d_e6860d97.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some US lawmakers capitalize on Ukrainian conflict — US Representative</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062555</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062555</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Representative Anna Paulina Luna noted that some lawmakers openly speak against efforts to settle the conflict in Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Representative Luna says not supporting money allocation to Kiev</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062557</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062557</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Anna Paulina Luna stressed that she "never voted for a single dollar to go to Ukraine"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan government condemns tanker capture by the US</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062559</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062559</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the government communique, this "egregiously criminal act" was made in violation of norms of international law, the maritime navigation convention and the UN Charter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep State wants military conflict between the US and Russia, Gabbard says</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062563</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062563</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said that every time Donald Trump makes progress and moves closer and closer to that hope for peace, the warmongers in the deep state step up and try to do everything they can to stop it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says Putin open to Ukraine war talks with France’s Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Putin is ready to talk to France’s Emmanuel Macron over the war in Ukraine, the Russian president’s spokesman said in an interview published on Sunday.
Putin has “expressed readiness to engage in dialogue with Macron”, Dmitry Peskov told state news agency RIA Novosti.
“Therefore, if there is mutual political will, then this can only be assessed positively.”
Macron said this week he believed Europe should reach back out to Putin over ending the war.
“I believe that it’s in our interest...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/3723c012-0f7d-457f-94eb-987e61098f5a_9b32b615.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive San Francisco power outage leaves thousands in the dark</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A huge electricity outage hit San Francisco on Saturday, leaving 130,000 residents without power and prompting city authorities to ask residents to stay home, according to the utility provider and the mayor.
Large parts of the west coast tech hub, which has a population of more than 800,000 people, were plunged into darkness with disruptions to public transport and many traffic lights not working on a busy Christmas shopping weekend.
“We are working with first responders and city officials on an...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/b3185e4f-b90c-4ace-836c-bcf49b3f87bb_2a29557f.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi Arabia’s discreet alcohol store opens doors to wealthy foreigners</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Saudi Arabia has quietly expanded access to its only store that sells alcohol, allowing wealthy foreign residents to buy booze in the latest step in the once-ultraconservative kingdom’s experiment in liberalisation.
There has been no official announcement of the decision, but word has got out, and long queues of cars and people can now be seen at the discreet, unmarked store in the Diplomatic Quarter of the Saudi capital, Riyadh.
The store opened in January 2024 for non-Muslim diplomats. The new...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/a53c9a65-a957-43f7-ae3a-2952e1b81149_cdd80239.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand doesn’t rule out possibility of a ceasefire in conflict zone with Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062595</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062595</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A special meeting of ASEAN foreign ministers was initiated by Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim and will be held on December 22 in Kuala Lumpur</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South African gun violence kills 9, wounds 10 in pub shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Nine people have died and at least 10 others were wounded after a group of gunmen carried out a shooting at a South African pub during the early hours of Sunday, authorities said.
The incident occurred just before 1am in the township of Bekkersdal, which is located 46 kilometres (28 miles) west of Johannesburg. It is the second mass shooting to happen in South Africa in three weeks.
About 12 unknown suspects in a white minibus and a silver sedan opened fire at pub patrons at KwaNoxolo tavern, in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/0cd9d4b0-dccd-4236-83fb-1f764b3afde1_9e0ef332.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron, on UAE visit, announces new French aircraft carrier</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>French President Emmanuel Macron said on Sunday he had given the official go-ahead to replace his country’s flagship, the nuclear-powered Charles de Gaulle aircraft carrier.
That vessel, the only nuclear-powered carrier outside the US Navy, entered service in 2001 following more than a decade of construction.
“In line with the last two military programming laws, and after a thorough and comprehensive review, I have decided to equip France with a new aircraft carrier,” Macron said, speaking...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/3c0cd7c3-6ab4-4d9e-a531-ca29d4a26132_3ced8932.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump tariffs push Swiss pharma CEO to urge price alignment with US</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Roche’s Chief Executive an interview with Swiss media published on Sunday called for Switzerland to pay more for new drugs, to bring prices in line with those paid by Washington.
The Swiss pharmaceutical giant’s US subsidiary Genentech figures among 14 pharmaceutical companies which have so far signed on to US President Donald Trump’s push to cut some US drug prices.
Companies have been making these voluntary deals after Trump sent a letter to 17 major companies over the summer threatening...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/076e200f-c771-4230-b4b2-eeeec1c81cd7_48271cc2.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lukashenko says Belarus and Russia implement all agreements, almost no questions exist</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062675</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062675</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Lukashenko also thanked Putin for evaluating his speech at the session of the All-Belarusian National Assembly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron betrays Merz on expropriation of frozen Russian assets — FT</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062677</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062677</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"He knows that there will be a price to pay for that", also said a senior EU diplomat</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building cooperation with third countries important for EAEU — Lukashenko</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062679</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062679</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Minsk fully supports the search for new partners from among the states of the global majority, moving to those regions of the world where the EAEU nations are respected and expected</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war drags on as drone attack kills 10 in Darfur market</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A drone attack on a busy market in Sudan’s North Darfur state killed 10 people over the weekend, first responders said, without saying who was responsible.
The attack comes as fighting intensified elsewhere in the country, leading aid workers to be evacuated on Sunday from Kadugli, a besieged, famine-hit city in the south.
Since April 2023, Sudan’s army and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces have been locked in a conflict, which has killed tens of thousands of people, displaced nearly 12...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/16475f84-5b77-4521-a340-f76ad3453332_a7a87b60.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US is pursuing a third oil tanker near Venezuela, officials say</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>The US Coast Guard is pursuing ‌an oil tanker in international waters near Venezuela, officials told Reuters ‍on Sunday, in what would be the second such operation this weekend and the third in less than a week.
One of the officials said the tanker was under sanctions.
The ⁠officials, who were speaking on condition of anonymity, did not give a specific location for the operation.
The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday. US President Donald Trump last week...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/f95b4396-7c43-407c-8cfe-50c49719b007_098a8778.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elysee Palace silver steward arrested for stealing silverware worth up to US$47,000</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Three men will stand trial next year after a silver steward employed at the official residence of the French president was arrested this week for the theft of items of silverware and table service worth thousands of euros, the Paris prosecutor’s office said.
The Elysee Palace’s head steward reported the disappearance, with the estimated loss ranging between €15,000 and €40,000 (US$17,500-US$47,000).
The Sevres Manufactory – which supplied most of the furnishings – identified several of the...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/66a17c5b-5717-443e-ab09-2c426ac677c8_9060a565.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top US official defends partial release of Epstein files as Democrats cry foul</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche on Sunday defended the Justice Department’s decision to release just a fraction of the Jeffrey Epstein files by the congressionally mandated deadline as necessary to protect survivors of sexual abuse by the disgraced financier.
Blanche pledged that the Trump administration eventually would meet its obligation required by law. However, he stressed that the department was obliged to act with caution as it goes about making public thousands of documents that...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/798bb936-94b8-4a92-a046-75a3ff708947_ad4d6e25.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <title>World News Unified Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.theguardian.com</link>
    <description>Merged World News RSS</description>
  </channel>
</rss>
