<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <item><title>Scientist Hu Haitao leaves US for China, Mexico tariff shock: 5 weekend reads you missed</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3337269/scientist-hu-haitao-leaves-us-china-mexico-tariff-shock-5-weekend-reads-you-missed?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:30:08 +0000</pubDate><description>We have put together stories from our coverage last weekend to help you stay informed about news across Asia and beyond. If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider subscribing.
1. Mexico’s 50% tariff shock shuts Asia’s North American trade bypass

2. China warns India: ‘don’t even think about stealing our 6th Dalai Lama’

3. Hong Kong district officer apologises over outfit choice at firefighter’s funeral

4. Thailand’s tourism crown slips as troubles in paradise mount

5....</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/c76f83e4-5116-402f-9126-a2d0b9c538c7_b474ee7b.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Republika Srpska’s new president maintains course of friendship with Russia — MFA</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062803</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062803</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:45:41 +0000</pubDate><description>Yury Pilipson recalled that "the early presidential elections in the Republika Srpska held on November 23 were the result of a campaign launched under pressure from Western countries to illegally remove Milorad Dodik, the leader of the Serbs in Bosnia and Herzegovina, from power"</description></item><item><title>No new Russia-US meeting on irritants planned yet — embassy in Moscow</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062805</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062805</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:19:57 +0000</pubDate><description>At the same time, US diplomats noted that Washington considers "the channel of bilateral operations as a constructive and permanent platform for negotiations to stabilize the work of the missions"</description></item><item><title>Brussels promised that sanctions would crush Russia, but they destroyed Europe — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062807</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062807</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:22:38 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that this is the price of poor decision-making and that negotiations are needed</description></item><item><title>European Commission becomes ‘Titanic’ dragging EU down with it — magazine</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062817</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062817</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:34:06 +0000</pubDate><description>According to journalist Rafael Pinto Borges, Brussels has experienced institutional decline, which the European Commission prefers to ignore</description></item><item><title>Trump administration recalls heads of nearly 30 foreign diplomatic missions — news agency</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062819</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062819</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:03:54 +0000</pubDate><description>According to its information, the heads of US missions abroad have been notified that their terms in their current positions will expire in January</description></item><item><title>No Ukraine ceasefire breakthrough despite ‘productive and constructive’ talks</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337262/no-ukraine-ceasefire-breakthrough-despite-productive-and-constructive-talks?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:30:27 +0000</pubDate><description>US and Ukrainian envoys issued a joint statement on Sunday that hailed “productive and constructive” talks in Miami but did not announce any apparent breakthrough in efforts to end the war with Russia.
Top representatives from both Ukraine and Russia, as well as Kyiv’s European allies, have been in southern Florida over the past several days for a series of separate talks hosted by US President Donald Trump’s special envoy, Steve Witkoff.
The meetings were the latest in a weeks-long diplomatic...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/5cdf1648-0b89-46bb-b500-fb0b2c4cd139_b36102a0.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>US tanker with Venezuelan oil left for US — official</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062821</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062821</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:51:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Vice President and Hydrocarbons Minister Delcy Rodriguez also posted a video of the tanker leaving port</description></item><item><title>Witkoff calls Russia-US consultations on Ukraine ‘productive, constructive’</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062797</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062797</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:34:55 +0000</pubDate><description>Moscow highly values Washington's efforts to settle the conflict and strengthen global security, he added</description></item><item><title>US Air Force fighter jet intercepts aircraft for approaching Trump's residence</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062785</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062785</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate><description>F‑16 intercepted an aircraft that entered restricted airspace over Palm Beach, NORAD reported</description></item><item><title>Continuation of Ukraine conflict beneficial to politicians, arms dealers, bankers — Orban</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062787</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062787</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:14:57 +0000</pubDate><description>Hungarian Prime Minister emphasized that Europeans deserve better, because Europe needs peace</description></item><item><title>US, Ukraine discuss sequence of next steps during consultations — Witkoff</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062769</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062769</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:44:21 +0000</pubDate><description>According to the Special Representative of the US president, the parties, in particular, held "a separate constructive meeting"</description></item><item><title>Israeli foreign minister urges Jews to move to Israel a week after Sydney attack</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337254/israeli-foreign-minister-urges-jews-move-israel-week-after-sydney-attack?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:11:13 +0000</pubDate><description>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar called on Sunday for Jews in Western countries to move to Israel to escape rising antisemitism, one week after 15 were shot dead at a Jewish event in Sydney.
“Jews have the right to live in safety everywhere. But we see and fully understand what is happening, and we have a certain historical experience.
“Today, Jews are being hunted across the world,” Saar said at a public candle lighting marking the last day of the Jewish festival of Hanukkah.
“Today I call...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/e5780976-ffcf-4b84-b7f9-b4d3b9443b98_8ea3fbf3.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Ukrainian journalists say took pictures of Mindich in Israel</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062775</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062775</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:14:30 +0000</pubDate><description>The details are promised to be released later</description></item><item><title>Thousands cheer as the sun rises on winter solstice at Britain’s Stonehenge</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337253/thousands-cheer-sun-rises-winter-solstice-britains-stonehenge?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate><description>Thousands of people cheered and danced around Stonehenge as the sun rose over the prehistoric stone circle on Sunday, the winter solstice.
The crowds, many dressed as druids and pagans, had gathered before dawn, waiting patiently in the dark, cold field in Wiltshire, southwest England. Some sang and beat drums while others took time to reflect among the huge stone pillars.
Many make the pilgrimage to the stone circle every summer and winter and consider it a spiritual experience.
The ancient...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/945907eb-e8b8-4086-842e-b15d4daeaa9e_8c84218a.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>Maduro condemns attacks on tankers carrying Venezuelan oil</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062763</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062763</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:05:51 +0000</pubDate><description>He noted that the Venezuelan people and all social strata of society remain steadfast in defending peace and national stability</description></item><item><title>US in pursuit of third tanker off coast of Venezuela — Bloomberg</title><link>https://tass.com/world/2062755</link><guid>https://tass.com/world/2062755</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:51:49 +0000</pubDate><description>The reason is Donald Trump's tightening of the oil blockade against the government of Nicolas Maduro, noted Bloomberg</description></item><item><title>Nigerian government frees 130 kidnapped Catholic schoolchildren</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337252/nigerian-government-frees-130-kidnapped-catholic-schoolchildren?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:53:26 +0000</pubDate><description>Nigerian authorities have secured the release of 130 kidnapped schoolchildren taken by gunmen from a Catholic school in November, a presidential spokesman said on Sunday, after 100 were freed earlier this month.
“Another 130 abducted Niger state pupils released, none left in captivity,” Sunday Dare said in a post on social media.
In late November, hundreds of pupils and staff were kidnapped from St Mary’s boarding school in north-central Niger state though the exact number and whether all are...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/97a37352-687c-42c1-ab81-c29a3500e5e8_a622b7ba.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item><title>UK’s Starmer discusses Ukraine peace efforts in call with Trump</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</link><guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337251/uks-starmer-discusses-ukraine-peace-efforts-call-trump?utm_source=rss_feed</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:18:11 +0000</pubDate><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer discussed efforts to achieve a “just ‌and lasting end” to the war in Ukraine on Sunday with US President Donald Trump, Starmer’s Downing Street office said in a statement, after talks between officials in Florida.
“The two leaders began by reflecting ⁠on the war in Ukraine,” Starmer’s office said in a readout of the call, adding they had discussed the work of the so-called Coalition of the Willing countries that have pledged to support Ukraine.
“The Prime...</description><media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/7da60daf-1470-4b23-8368-3fe5bce75459_bd8a2294.jpg" medium="image"/></item><item>
      <title>Russia-Africa Forum agree plan of actions for 2026-2029 — top Egyptian diplomat</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062509</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062509</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to Badr Abdelatty, Russia and African countries agreed to "develop relations and hold political consultations on the basis of the norms of international law and the principle of non-interference into countries’ domestic affairs"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, Qatar, Egypt, Turkey report progress in implementing Gaza ceasefire phase one</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062515</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062515</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>As follows from the document, they held talks in Miami, Florida</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyz president arrives in Russia on working visit</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062519</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062519</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Sadyr Japarov has arrived to take part in the meeting of the Supreme Eurasian Economic Council and the informal meeting of CIS leaders in St. Petersburg, the press service of the Kyrgyz leader said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aggression against Venezuela may lead to humanitarian catastrophe — Brazilian leader</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062521</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062521</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva called on the countries of the region to consolidate their efforts to preserve it as a zone of peace and stability</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Egyptian diplomat describes Miami talks on Gaza as good</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062523</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062523</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Egyptian Foreign Minister Badr Abdelatty also expressed hope for the soonest beginning of the implementation of the Gaza deal second phase</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky admits that Kiev will not be able to finance 800,000-strong army</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062527</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062527</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Zelensky said that he maintains dialogue with Western leaders concerning partial financing of Ukrainian army at the expense of the partners</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US department confirms detention of tanker near Venezuelan coast</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062533</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062533</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"The United States will continue to pursue the illicit movement of sanctioned oil," the Head of the Department of Homeland Security Kristi Noem said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanker apprehended by the US near Venezuela sailed under flag of Panama — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062535</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062535</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the newspaper, the cargo belonged to an oil trader from China that supplies oil from Venezuela to Chinese refineries</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz finds himself in isolation in Europe due to position on Russian assets — newspaper</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062545</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062545</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>German Chancellor attempted till the last "to praise advantages of the de facto expropriation of Russian assets, downplaying risks at the same time," the newspaper said</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US National Intelligence confident Russia not planning to control entire Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062553</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062553</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard called such information about Russia's plans "a lie and propaganda"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump at ‘risk of becoming the deep state’ after Epstein file omissions</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337207/trump-risk-becoming-deep-state-after-epstein-file-omissions?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Extensive redactions and the limited number of documents released related to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein angered some Republicans and did little to defuse a scandal threatening the party ahead of the 2026 midterm election.
The Trump administration touted this week’s release of a cache of Epstein-related files as a show of transparency, but a handful of Republican lawmakers and right-wing media figures joined Democrats in ‍blasting Friday’s disclosures as inadequate and possibly in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/ea215dd0-b670-4b62-93dc-10d73ab67e6d_e6860d97.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some US lawmakers capitalize on Ukrainian conflict — US Representative</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062555</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062555</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Representative Anna Paulina Luna noted that some lawmakers openly speak against efforts to settle the conflict in Ukraine</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Representative Luna says not supporting money allocation to Kiev</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062557</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062557</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Anna Paulina Luna stressed that she "never voted for a single dollar to go to Ukraine"</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan government condemns tanker capture by the US</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062559</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062559</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>According to the government communique, this "egregiously criminal act" was made in violation of norms of international law, the maritime navigation convention and the UN Charter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep State wants military conflict between the US and Russia, Gabbard says</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062563</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062563</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said that every time Donald Trump makes progress and moves closer and closer to that hope for peace, the warmongers in the deep state step up and try to do everything they can to stop it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says Putin open to Ukraine war talks with France’s Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3337214/russia-says-putin-open-ukraine-war-talks-frances-macron?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Vladimir Putin is ready to talk to France’s Emmanuel Macron over the war in Ukraine, the Russian president’s spokesman said in an interview published on Sunday.
Putin has “expressed readiness to engage in dialogue with Macron”, Dmitry Peskov told state news agency RIA Novosti.
“Therefore, if there is mutual political will, then this can only be assessed positively.”
Macron said this week he believed Europe should reach back out to Putin over ending the war.
“I believe that it’s in our interest...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/3723c012-0f7d-457f-94eb-987e61098f5a_9b32b615.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive San Francisco power outage leaves thousands in the dark</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337215/massive-san-francisco-power-outage-leaves-thousands-dark?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A huge electricity outage hit San Francisco on Saturday, leaving 130,000 residents without power and prompting city authorities to ask residents to stay home, according to the utility provider and the mayor.
Large parts of the west coast tech hub, which has a population of more than 800,000 people, were plunged into darkness with disruptions to public transport and many traffic lights not working on a busy Christmas shopping weekend.
“We are working with first responders and city officials on an...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/b3185e4f-b90c-4ace-836c-bcf49b3f87bb_2a29557f.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi Arabia’s discreet alcohol store opens doors to wealthy foreigners</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337222/saudi-arabias-discreet-alcohol-store-opens-doors-wealthy-foreigners?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Saudi Arabia has quietly expanded access to its only store that sells alcohol, allowing wealthy foreign residents to buy booze in the latest step in the once-ultraconservative kingdom’s experiment in liberalisation.
There has been no official announcement of the decision, but word has got out, and long queues of cars and people can now be seen at the discreet, unmarked store in the Diplomatic Quarter of the Saudi capital, Riyadh.
The store opened in January 2024 for non-Muslim diplomats. The new...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/a53c9a65-a957-43f7-ae3a-2952e1b81149_cdd80239.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand doesn’t rule out possibility of a ceasefire in conflict zone with Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062595</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062595</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A special meeting of ASEAN foreign ministers was initiated by Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim and will be held on December 22 in Kuala Lumpur</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South African gun violence kills 9, wounds 10 in pub shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337230/south-african-gun-violence-kills-9-wounds-10-pub-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Nine people have died and at least 10 others were wounded after a group of gunmen carried out a shooting at a South African pub during the early hours of Sunday, authorities said.
The incident occurred just before 1am in the township of Bekkersdal, which is located 46 kilometres (28 miles) west of Johannesburg. It is the second mass shooting to happen in South Africa in three weeks.
About 12 unknown suspects in a white minibus and a silver sedan opened fire at pub patrons at KwaNoxolo tavern, in...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/0cd9d4b0-dccd-4236-83fb-1f764b3afde1_9e0ef332.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron, on UAE visit, announces new French aircraft carrier</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3337239/saudi-arabia-expands-alcohol-access-non-muslim-residents?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>French President Emmanuel Macron said on Sunday he had given the official go-ahead to replace his country’s flagship, the nuclear-powered Charles de Gaulle aircraft carrier.
That vessel, the only nuclear-powered carrier outside the US Navy, entered service in 2001 following more than a decade of construction.
“In line with the last two military programming laws, and after a thorough and comprehensive review, I have decided to equip France with a new aircraft carrier,” Macron said, speaking...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/3c0cd7c3-6ab4-4d9e-a531-ca29d4a26132_3ced8932.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump tariffs push Swiss pharma CEO to urge price alignment with US</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337244/trump-tariffs-push-swiss-pharma-ceo-urge-price-alignment-us?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Roche’s Chief Executive an interview with Swiss media published on Sunday called for Switzerland to pay more for new drugs, to bring prices in line with those paid by Washington.
The Swiss pharmaceutical giant’s US subsidiary Genentech figures among 14 pharmaceutical companies which have so far signed on to US President Donald Trump’s push to cut some US drug prices.
Companies have been making these voluntary deals after Trump sent a letter to 17 major companies over the summer threatening...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/076e200f-c771-4230-b4b2-eeeec1c81cd7_48271cc2.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lukashenko says Belarus and Russia implement all agreements, almost no questions exist</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062675</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062675</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Lukashenko also thanked Putin for evaluating his speech at the session of the All-Belarusian National Assembly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macron betrays Merz on expropriation of frozen Russian assets — FT</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062677</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062677</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>"He knows that there will be a price to pay for that", also said a senior EU diplomat</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building cooperation with third countries important for EAEU — Lukashenko</title>
      <link>https://tass.com/world/2062679</link>
      <guid>https://tass.com/world/2062679</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Minsk fully supports the search for new partners from among the states of the global majority, moving to those regions of the world where the EAEU nations are respected and expected</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war drags on as drone attack kills 10 in Darfur market</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3337246/sudan-war-drags-drone-attack-kills-10-darfur-market?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A drone attack on a busy market in Sudan’s North Darfur state killed 10 people over the weekend, first responders said, without saying who was responsible.
The attack comes as fighting intensified elsewhere in the country, leading aid workers to be evacuated on Sunday from Kadugli, a besieged, famine-hit city in the south.
Since April 2023, Sudan’s army and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces have been locked in a conflict, which has killed tens of thousands of people, displaced nearly 12...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/16475f84-5b77-4521-a340-f76ad3453332_a7a87b60.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US is pursuing a third oil tanker near Venezuela, officials say</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3337248/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>The US Coast Guard is pursuing ‌an oil tanker in international waters near Venezuela, officials told Reuters ‍on Sunday, in what would be the second such operation this weekend and the third in less than a week.
One of the officials said the tanker was under sanctions.
The ⁠officials, who were speaking on condition of anonymity, did not give a specific location for the operation.
The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Sunday. US President Donald Trump last week...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/f95b4396-7c43-407c-8cfe-50c49719b007_098a8778.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elysee Palace silver steward arrested for stealing silverware worth up to US$47,000</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3337249/elysee-palace-silver-steward-arrested-stealing-silverware-worth-us47000?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Three men will stand trial next year after a silver steward employed at the official residence of the French president was arrested this week for the theft of items of silverware and table service worth thousands of euros, the Paris prosecutor’s office said.
The Elysee Palace’s head steward reported the disappearance, with the estimated loss ranging between €15,000 and €40,000 (US$17,500-US$47,000).
The Sevres Manufactory – which supplied most of the furnishings – identified several of the...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/66a17c5b-5717-443e-ab09-2c426ac677c8_9060a565.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top US official defends partial release of Epstein files as Democrats cry foul</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <guid>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3337250/top-us-official-defends-partial-release-epstein-files-democrats-cry-foul?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>US Deputy Attorney General Todd Blanche on Sunday defended the Justice Department’s decision to release just a fraction of the Jeffrey Epstein files by the congressionally mandated deadline as necessary to protect survivors of sexual abuse by the disgraced financier.
Blanche pledged that the Trump administration eventually would meet its obligation required by law. However, he stressed that the department was obliged to act with caution as it goes about making public thousands of documents that...</description>
      <media:content url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/22/798bb936-94b8-4a92-a046-75a3ff708947_ad4d6e25.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <title>World News Unified Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.theguardian.com</link>
    <description>Merged World News RSS</description>
  </channel>
</rss>
